奇遇電影字幕組
QY-174
更多資訊請關注官方公眾號：cinematik
翻譯： @阿囤小兄弟  @一隻醉丁  @不見老阿
翻譯： @movie404  @魚飼料1  @Tien_Sun
校對：@一個Delpy     @Florrie_likkke
時間軸：@Edandelion_   @一隻醉丁   @33-eR
@-GOOEY     @沒什麼能難倒LeoQ
特效： @一隻醉丁
[海邊的曼徹斯特為美國馬薩諸塞州的一座小城鎮]
海邊的曼徹斯特
世界上有很多東西是他不懂
...A lot of stuff that he just doesn't understand
但是我懂的
about the world that I understand
我就靠它來過日子呢
that makes... it makes all my actions when I move through the world...
我之所以能做得更好 是因為我能看到世界像地圖一樣
I do things better because i can see it all laid out
在我面前展開  你看過地圖嗎
like a map. Have you ever looked at a map?
- 看過      - 你知道怎麼看地圖嗎
- Yes.        - Do you know how to read a map?
要是我沒記錯的話
if I'm not mistaken.
- 你知道怎麼看地圖嗎      - 知道
- Do you know how to read a map?        - Yeah.
你爸爸是個大好人
Your father's a perfectly good guy,
可是這個世界上
but there's a lot of stuff
還有很多我知道
that he just doesn't understand about the world
- 而他不知道的事情      - 我爸爸
- that I understand.        - My dad--
- 等等 聽著      - 我爸爸
- Wait. Listen.        - My daddy's--
我都還沒問你問題呢
I haven't asked you a question yet.
我還沒問你問題呢
I haven't asked you a question.
- 聽著 噓      - 我爸爸
- Listen. Shh.       - My daddy--
聽著 別跟你爸說 閉嘴 安靜
don't tell your father. Shut up! Be quiet.
噓 安靜 我還沒問你問題呢
Shush. I haven't asked you the question yet.
我什麼都還沒問呢 聽好了
I haven't asked you anything. Listen. Shh.
安靜 沒事 別擔心
Quiet. We got it. Don't worry about it.
聽著
Listen.
如果你可以帶一個人跟你上島
if you could take one guy to an island with you
你知道他會保護你 因為他是最厲害的人
and you knew you'd be safe because he was the best man
他會想辦法活下去
and he was going to figure out how to survive,
他會做各種東西
he was going to make everything--
他會把這座島變成一個美好的地方
make the world a good place on the island,
他會讓你快樂
he was going to keep you happy,
他會…不管怎樣 他都是這個差事的最佳人選
he-- this is the best man for the job, no matter what,
如果要你在我和你爸之間選
if it was between me and your father,
- 你會選誰      - 我爸爸
- who would you say?        - My daddy.
我不明白 等等
I don't see-- hang on a second.
等一下 聽著
Hang on a second. Listen.
你肯定理解錯這個問題了
I think you're wrong about that.
雖然是由你來選
It's your choice to make,
但是我想讓你知道
but I want you to understand something:
有很多…
That there's a lot of--
嘿 撿起來… 什麼情況 這是怎麼回事
hey. Pick up-- what hap-- what is that?
不可以把魚竿隨便丟在這裏
You can't leave your fishing rod like that.
我不知道它為什麼一直滴水
I don't know why the hell it keeps dripping.
一晚上滴個不停
All night long-- drip, drip, drip.
這破玩意兒我都修了十回了
I've had the fucking thing repaired ten times.
你得換一個新的塞子
You need a new stopper.
那就行了?
Is that it?
你看塞子的邊緣都爛成什麼樣了
Your stopper's--it's rotted all around the edges,
沒辦法密封
so it's not making a seal.
所以水滴到盆裏了
The water's going to drip through to the bowl.
我可以
I could, uh--
我明天可以給你帶個新的過來
I could bring you a new one tomorrow.
或者也許你可以考慮把整套裝置換了
Or you might want to consider replacing the whole apparatus.
你覺得怎麼辦合適
What do you recommend?
嗯 我可以先把塞子換了
I could replace the stopper first.
如果不管用
If that doesn't work,
再來幫你更換整套傢伙
I could replace the whole apparatus.
你就沒點專業建議嗎
You can't give me a professional recommendation?
反正隨你
it's really up to you.
明天
Tomorrow
我嫂子和侄子們要來
my sister-in-law's coming over with the nephews.
我得去把車開回來
I got to take the car in.
不 是我妹妹珍妮的長女的成人禮
No, it's my sister jeanine's oldest daughter's bat mitzvah.
我等著到時候被無聊到死
I'm looking forward to being bored to death.
不是 那丫頭不想辦 她爸爸也不想辦
the girl doesn't want it, her father doesn't want it,
我就更別提了
and don't even ask me.
七個小時的車程
Seven hours in the car.
我真的會想抹了自己的脖子
I could really slit my throat.
不過那幾個小丫頭還挺討人喜歡的
But oh, well. The little girls are charming.
李 真不好意思
Lee, I'm so sorry.
沒事
That's okay.
實在是很噁心
This is so gross.
沒關係
That's all right.
不 讓他來
No, tell him to come.
好的 嗯
Okay. Yeah.
不過辛迪 跟你說件事
But-- but-- but, Cindy, i have to tell you something.
我好像愛上我的修理工了
I'm, like, in love with my janitor.
會不會很變態
Is that sick?
你對你的修理工有沒有過非分之想
Have you ever had a sexual fantasy about your handyman?
嗯 感覺很奇怪 因為他正在
Well, it's awkward because he's literally, like,
清理我馬桶裏塞住的屎
cleaning the shit out of my toilet bowl right now,
而且我覺得我現在這樣真是沒什麼魅力可言
and I don't think I'm at my most alluring.
嗯 也許你說得對
Yeah, maybe you're right.
畢竟不是在社交場合碰到他…
It's not like i met him socially.
好的 謝謝你 辛迪
Okay, thank you, Cindy.
行 二十分鐘吧 拜
Okay. Like 20 minutes. Bye.
你好 搞定了
Uh, hi. All set.
非常感謝
Thank you so much.
不用謝
You're welcome.
我能給你一點小費[小建議]嗎
Can I give you a tip?
你是說你要提建議嗎
You mean like a suggestion?
不 我是說 小費
No. I mean like a tip.
哦
Oh.
好 謝謝
Okay. Thank you.
- 那好      - 好
- Okay.         - Okay.
晚安
Good night.
晚安 再見
Good night. Goodbye.
這該死的水管我得修多少遍才行
I mean, how many times do I have to fix these fucking pipes?
我每次一洗澡
Every time I take a shower,
公寓裏就跟發大水一樣
the entire apartment has a flood.
我真是被折騰瘋了
It's driving me insane.
我明天帶管道工過來
Well, I'll get you a plumber here tomorrow,
不過我們估計得把瓷磚敲開
but I'd say we're going to have to break through the tile
把漏水的部位隔離開來 因為下面已經積了很多水了
and isolate the leak because there's quite a lot of water down there.
可是你怎麼知道是我家的問題 為什麼問題就出在我家呢
How do you know it's me? Why is it automatically me?
因為如果是樓上的問題
Because if it was coming from higher up,
你的天花板或者牆上
you'd have water damage in your ceiling
會滲水的 但它們都是乾的
or in your wall, and it's all dry.
好吧
Great.
可能只是縫隙漏水的問題
It might just be the caulking.
浴缸四周都要重新封一遍
This whole tub needs to be recaulked.
最近幾個小時你是不是洗澡了
Have you taken a bath or a shower in the last couple of hours?
是啊
Yes.
那問題就在這了
It might just be that.
好吧 你打算怎麼找漏水點
Okay. And how are you planning to find that out?
我們可以把淋浴打開
Well, we could run the shower
看水會不會滴到樓下
and see if it drips downstairs.
你是想讓我現在洗個澡嗎
Oh, you want me to take a shower right now?
不是
No.
你是想讓我現在洗澡
You want me to take a shower right now
你在旁邊站著
while you stand there watching to see
看水會不會漏到樓下弗雷德裏克家嗎
if it drips into the Fredrichs' apartment?
我他媽才不管你幹什麼 奧爾森太太
I don't give a fuck what you do, Mrs. Olsen.
我只想把這該死的漏水修好
I'm just trying to fix the fucking leak.
我不喜歡這樣
I-- I didn't like that.
你居然敢這樣跟我說話
How dare you talk to me like that.
你他媽給我滾出去
Get the fuck out of my fucking house.
好的
Okay.
趁我還沒報警 滾出老娘家
Get the fuck out of my fucking house before I call the police.
好吧
All right.
你聽不見嗎 我說了滾出去
Did you hear me? I said get out.
我沒法滾 你堵著門呢
I can't. You're blocking the doorway.
你他媽什麼毛病啊
What the fuck's the matter with you?
你不能那樣跟住戶說話
You can't talk to the tenants like that.
聽著 李 你活兒幹得好
Look, Lee, you do good work.
人又可靠
You're dependable.
但是我老是收到投訴
But I get these complaints all the time.
說你沒禮貌 不友好
You're rude, you're unfriendly.
連"早上好"也不說 拜託 別這樣行嗎
You won't say good morning. I mean, come on.
埃默裏先生 我給他們修管道
Mr. Emery, i fix the plumbing,
幫他們扔垃圾 給他們刷牆
take out the garbage, paint their apartments.
還干電工的活兒
I do electrical work,
你我都知道這是違法的
which we both know is against the law.
我準時上班
I show up on time.
還要負責四棟樓
I'm working four buildings,
錢倒是都進了你的腰包
and you're getting all the money.
你想怎麼樣就怎麼樣吧
So do whatever you're gonna do.
你到底給不給奧爾森太太道歉
Would you be willing to apologize to Mrs. Olsen?
道什麼歉
For what?
好吧 好吧 我去跟她談談
All right. All right. I'll talk to her.
- 嘿 李      - 謝謝
- Hey, Lee.        - Thanks.
- 你怎麼樣      - 挺好的
- How are you doing?        - Good.
最近還挺順利的吧
How's things going, all right?
嗯
Yeah.
比賽看了嗎
Watch the game?
看了
Yeah, I did.
你覺得他們有機會嗎
You think they got a shot?
- 沒有      - 你敢肯定?
- No.        - You bet?
我肯定
Yeah, I would.
他們輸了前兩場
They dropped the first two.
接下來三場照樣會輸
They're going to lose the next three.
- 給你      - 謝謝
- Here you go.        - Thanks.
天吶 對不起
Oh, my god. I'm so sorry.
沒事
That's okay.
潑到你身上沒
Did I get you?
是的
Yes.
- 潑到你身上了啊      - 沒關係
- I got you. Uh...        - That's okay.
- 我給你拿點紙巾      - 我沒事
- Let me get you some napkins.        - I'm okay.
嘿 萊尼 能不能給我點紙巾
Hey, Lenny, can i grab some napkins?
謝謝
Thanks.
Thank you.
給
Here.
謝謝
Thanks.
沒事
It's okay.
我潑了你一身啤酒
Well, now I spilled my beer all over you,
我叫莎倫
my name's Sharon.
嗯 不要緊
uh, it's okay.
你叫...
And you are?
李
Uh, Lee.
他過來了
Here he comes.
你好嗎
How you doing?
- 你好啊      - 很好 我挺好的
- How you doing?        - Good. I'm good.
我想問一下 你們認識我嗎
Hey, can I ask you guys, do you know me?
- 不認識      - 我也不認識
- Uh, I don't think so.        - Yeah, I don't think so either.
我們從來沒見過？
We never met?
- 沒見過      - 對 沒見過
- No.        - No, not yet.
- 沒見過      - 沒有
- No, I don't think so.        - No.
那你們他媽的看我幹什麼
So what the fuck are you looking at me for?
- 什麼      - 我說你他媽看我幹什麼
- Excuse me?        - I said what the fuck are you looking at me for?
- 你他媽給我滾蛋      - 先生 我們真的沒看你…
- Hey, take a fuckin' walk.        - Sir, we weren't looking at you.
不不不 別跟這混蛋道歉
No, don't apologize to this asshole.
- 你他媽滾蛋      - 我們真的沒在看你
- Take a fuckin' hike.        - We weren't looking at you, seriously.
拜託 哥們 喂
Come on, man! Hey!
放開我 我要滾蛋
Let me go! I gotta go take a hike!
我他媽要滾蛋
I wanna take a fuckin' hike!
喂 我是李
Hello, this is Lee.
哦 好的
Oh. Okay.
什麼時候的事
When did that happen?
他現在怎麼樣了
Well, how's he doing now?
不 別告訴他
No, don't do that.
我現在就過來
I'm gonna come up there right now.
一個半小時內就到
I'll be up there in an hour and a half.
可以嗎
Okay?
謝謝你
Thank you.
再見
Bye.
埃默裏先生 還是我 我聯繫過何賽了
Mr. Emery, it's Lee again. I contacted Jose.
他至少能幫我代班到週五晚上
He can cover me till Friday night at least.
然後吉恩·麥克蒂維會負責到我回來
Uh, after that, Gene Macadavey will take over until I get back.
弗雷德裏克家的天花板我就先不管了
Um, I wouldn't do anything with Mr.and Mrs. Fredrich's ceiling
等你找到專業的管道工再說吧
until you you get a real plumber in there.
那你準備怎麼辦呢
But what are you gonna do?
有什麼消息我會第一時間跟你說
I will, uh, let you know as soon as I have more information.
我至少要在曼徹斯特待一周
I should be in Manchester a week at least.
非常感謝 再見
Thank you very much. Bye.
快點
Come on!
走啊
Go!
- 嘿 李      - 他去世了嗎
- Hey, Lee.        - Is he dead?
節哀順變 李
I'm sorry, Lee.
他一個小時前過世了
He passed away about an hour ago.
- 噢      - 節哀順變
- Oh.        - I'm so sorry.
- 你見到他了嗎      - 沒有
- Did you see him?        - No.
- 我是說 我送他來醫院的      - 喬治送他來醫院的
- I mean, I brought him in.        - George brought him in.
我們早上正在檢查船隻
We were looking at the boat this morning,
他就...
and he just--
我也搞不清 就像是摔倒了
I don't know, he just, like, fell over.
一開始我以為他在開玩笑
I thought he was kidding me at first.
然後我叫了救護車
Then I called the ambulance, and, uh...
然後 就這樣了
That was it.
我去叫穆勒醫生 告訴他你來了
I'll just call Dr. Muller and tell him that you're here.
貝特尼醫生去哪了
Where's Dr. Betheny?
她在休產假 哦 他來了
Oh, she's on maternity leave. Here he is.
李 我是穆勒醫生 我們通過電話
Lee, I'm Dr. muller. We spoke on the phone.
- 嗯 嗨      - 我非常非常遺憾
- Yeah, hi.        - I'm very, very sorry.
- 謝謝      - 你好 喬治
- Thank you.        - Hello, George.
- 嘿 吉姆      - 你還好吧
- Hiya, Jim.        - How you holding up?
還行吧 你也知道
Oh, great, you know
- 嗯 真是難過的一天      - 是啊
- It's a very sad day.        - Yeah.
我哥在哪
Where's my brother?
他在樓下 願意的話 你可以去看他
Oh, he's downstairs. You can see him if you want.
他怎麼了
What happened to him?
心臟驟停
Just a cardiac arrest.
他的心臟十分脆弱
You know his heart's very weak at this point.
然後就停止跳動了
It just gave out.
我很遺憾你沒能及時趕到
I'm really sorry you couldn't get here in time,
但是我在電話裏跟你說到…
but as I told you before--
操他媽的
aw, fuck this.
對不起
Sorry.
- 沒關係      - 真沒事 哥們
- That's okay, buddy.        - That's perfectly all right.
有人通知我叔叔嗎
Did anybody call my uncle?
就是唐尼叔叔
It's their uncle Donny.
嗯 我叔叔嬸嬸
Yeah, my aunt and uncle.
- 應該有人通知他們       - 沒有 李 沒通知
- Somebody should have called--        - no, Lee. Lee, no.
- 怎麼了      - 唐尼在明尼蘇達州找了個活
- What? What?        - Donny got a job in Minnesota.
- 有一陣兒了      - 明尼蘇達?
- Like, a while ago.        - Minnesota?
嗯 他在明尼蘇達的明尼通卡
Yeah, he got a job in some outfit
找到了工作
in minnetonka, Minnesota,
信不信由你
if you can believe that.
- 喬沒跟你說嗎      - 沒有
- Joe didn't tell you about that?        - No.
如果你需要的話 我可以打給他 李
I can call him if you want, Lee,
告訴他們這件事
and tell him what happened.
- 行 謝謝      - 哦 不用謝
- Okay, thanks.        - No problem.
跟他說一下這件事情
Tell him what happened.
跟他說我今晚會給他打電話
Tell him I'll call him tonight.
商量後事
Talk about arrangements.
誰通知一下我妻子
Somebody should call my wife.
- 你的…      - 前妻
- Your, uh, uh...        - Ex-wife.
- 你是說蘭迪      - 蘭迪
- You mean Randi?        - Randi.
- 對 抱歉 我是說蘭迪      - 沒關係
- Yes, I'm sorry. I meant Randi.        - That's okay.
我明白你的意思 交給我吧
I already thought of that. I'll take care of it.
- 行 謝謝      - 別客氣
- Okay. Thank you.        - No problem.
- 我能去看他了嗎      - 當然
- Can I see him now?        - Sure.
李 我可以在這裏等你
Lee, I can wait up here.
要是需要我幫忙的話
Lee, if you need anything.
好
Okay.
- 謝謝      - 嗯
- Thanks.        - Yeah.
需要紙巾嗎
Would you like a kleenex?
- 好的 謝謝      - 好
- Yeah, thanks. Yeah.        - Yeah.
麻煩給我點紙巾
Can I get a couple kleenex, please?
謝謝 親愛的
Thanks, hon.
- 對不起       - 沒事
- I'm sorry.        - Oh, please.
- 貝特尼醫生怎麼樣了      - 她挺好的
- How is Dr. betheny?        - Oh, she's doing very well.
剛生了一對雙胞胎女兒
She just had twin girls.
- 艾琳跟我說了      - 對啊
- Oh, Irene told me that.        - Yeah.
我下午就打電話告訴她這事
I call this afternoon and tell her what happened.
她以前對他很好
She was very good to him.
是啊
Yeah, she was.
這種病通常被稱為充血性心力衰竭
The disease is commonly referred to as congestive heart failure.
- 我的天吶      - 你很熟悉這個病嗎
- Oh, my god.        - Are you familiar with it?
- 不熟      - 那你"我的天"個什麼啊
- No.      - Then what are you saying "oh, my god" for?
- 因為...這是什麼病啊      - 她正跟咱們解釋呢 親愛的
- Because-- what is it?        - She's trying to explain it, honey.
- 抱歉 貝…      - 貝特尼
- I'm sorry, Dr. Beth--        - Betheny.
- 貝特尼 抱歉 我老是記不住      - 沒事
- Betheny, I'm sorry. I can never get it right.       - Not a problem.
所以 你剛才說
So you were saying.
它是心臟肌肉的逐漸退化
It's a gradual deterioration of the muscles of the heart.
通常發生在老年人身上
It's usually associated with older people.
但在極少數的情況下 也會發生在年輕人身上
But in rare cases, it will occur in a younger person.
有的人能活五十到六十年 只是偶爾發作一下
Some people live up to 50-60 years with just an occasional attack.
但是絕大多數患者都是週期性發作
But most people suffer periodic episodes,
就像你週一那次
like the one you had on Monday,
出現的類似於心臟病發作的癥狀
which mimic the symptoms of a heart attack,
它還會進一步削弱肌肉力量
and which further weaken the muscle.
讓你一整周 或是兩周都無法正常工作
They can put you out of commission for a week, two weeks.
你需要住院觀察 這樣我們就可以監控你的心臟
And you'll need to be hospitalized so we can monitor your heart,
因為心臟停搏的風險在這一兩周內較高
because the risk of cardiac arrest is elevated for a week or two.
- 我的天吶      - 沒事
- Oh, my god.        - It's okay.
但在兩次發作的間隙 絕大多數患者跟健康人沒兩樣
But in between, most people feel perfectly healthy
基本上可以正常生活
you can basically live a normal life.
等等 你說有些人活了五六十年是什麼意思
Wait. So what do you mean some people live to be 50-60 years?
你是說一共活了這麼多年
I mean, are you saying total?
還是確診後又活了五六十年
Or are saying when they're diagnosed with this?
還是什麼 你是什麼意思
Or what? What are you saying?
跟我說實話
And tell me the fuckin' truth.
一共
Total.
對於和您癥狀相近的病人來說
For most people with the particulars of your condition,
平均壽命一般為再活五到十年
the average life expectancy is five to ten years.
但是數據變動區間很大 你不是數據
The statistics vary widely. You're not a statistic.
而是活生生的人
You're just one person,
我們尚不清楚你的狀況會怎樣
and we don't know what's gonna happen to you yet.
但是這個病情況並不樂觀
But it's not a good disease.
有什麼病是樂觀的嗎
What is a good disease?
- 被毒藤刺了起皮疹      - 香港腳
- Poison Ivy.        - Athlete's foot?
- 這是個喜劇梗      - 埃莉斯 別鬧了
- It's a comedy routine.        - Elise, please.
- 老天啊      - 我的天吶
- For Christ's sake.        - Oh, my god!
我做什麼都是錯的
When am I gonna put one foot right?
- 能不能告訴我要怎麼辦      - 埃莉斯
- How about a hint?        - Elise...
- 爸爸      - 怎麼了
- Daddy.        - What?
她沒事
She's fine.
我們都很難過
We're all upset.
咱們都好好聽
We're all gonna listen,
然後想知道什麼就問什麼
then we're gonna ask any of the questions we wanna ask,
再一起想解決辦法 好嗎
and then we're gonna figure out what to do together, right?
- 好      - 當然
- Right.        - Sure.
所以 貝絲醫生 你剛才說
So you were saying, Dr. Beth.
- 是貝特尼醫生 爸      - 貝特尼醫生 爸 你記清楚好嗎
- Betheny, dad.        - It's Dr. Betheny, dad. Get it right.
我看不出來在這種情形下有什麼好笑的
I do not see where the humor lies in this situation.
- 埃莉斯 你要冷靜      - 不要
- Elise, you must calm down.        - No.
- 對不起 我不是真的要…      - 沒事沒事 不用道歉
- I'm sorry, I'm not trying to--        - no, no, don't.
不 行了 我不…
more. I'm not gonna. Nope.
- 埃莉斯 我給你倒杯水吧      - 不用了
- Elise, let me get you a glass of water.        - No.
- 爸 算了      - 對 算了 就像你一樣
- Daddy, forget it.        - Forget it like you.
大家都應該像你這樣
Everybody should be just like you.
你猜怎麼著 我受夠了在這唱黑臉
You know what? I am tired of being the bad guy here.
天吶 到底是誰住院啊
Jesus Christ! Who's in the fuckin' hospital here?
沒錯 所以我來唱黑臉
Right. Right. So I'll be the bad guy,
你住你的院 自己跟你兒子解釋這出笑話吧
and you be in the hospital and explain the jokes to your son.
- 我回家了      - 你要回家?
- I'm going home.        - You're going home?
- 你真回家啊      - 沒錯
- You're going home?        - Yep!
- 我去叫她回來      - 去她的
- Let me get her back.        - Fuck her.
- 你就會幹這種事      - 你能不能少說兩句
- Come on with that stuff already!        - Stop that shit!
謝謝你 托尼
Thank you, Tony.
謝謝你
Thank you.
我得去趟曼徹斯特
I have to get up to Manchester.
還沒有人告訴帕特裏克 對吧
Nobody told Patrick, right?
沒有 你讓我們等你過來再說
No, you had asked for us to wait for you to get here.
- 是的 謝謝      - 好
- Yes. Thank you.        - Okay.
那麼 接下來該怎麼做
So, um, what is the procedure now?
現在你要聯繫一家殯儀館來安排後面的事情
Oh, now you have to make arrangements with a funeral parlor.
他們基本上會把所有的事情都安排好的
And they pretty much take care of everything.
我連一家殯儀館都不知道
I don't know the name of one.
沒關係 我們可以幫你
That's all right. We can help you with that.
是啊
Oh, yeah.
他們會直接過來把他接走?
And they'll just come and pick him up?
- 是的      - 是
- Yeah.        - Yes.
- 我可以幫忙打電話 李      - 好
- I can make those calls, Lee.        - Okay.
如果你需要任何幫助的話 儘管說
Let me know if you need any help with anything.
好的 謝謝
Okay. Thank you. Hmm.
是啊 我們還得談談那條船
Yeah, we've gotta talk about the boat
還有網站
and the website,
等等東西
and all that.
沒問題 隨時找我
Sure. I'm around.
我得在學校放學之前趕到那裏 所以...
I gotta get up there before school let's out, so--
你只要簽字確認喬的遺物就行了
you just have to sign for Joe's belongings.
這邊
Right this way.
在這邊簽字
Just gotta sign right here.
喬的遺物在哪裏 就是放在這裏的那個塑料袋
Where's Joe's belongings? The plastic bag right here.
不好意思 稍等一下
Sorry. Give me a sec.
喬的遺物放在哪了
Where's Joe's belongings?
好 好 這很棒
All right, all right. That's good. Hup!
- 像這樣?      - 沒錯 不過別把你的大拇指放在魚線上
- Like that?        - Yeah, but keep your thumb off the line,
因為如果有魚上鉤 魚線就會直接把手指割破
because, if you get a strike, it's gonna slice it right open,
接下去會發生什麼你知道嗎
and you know what happens then?
- 什麼      - 鯊魚會聞到血腥味
- What?        - The sharks will smell the blood,
然後把這條船撕成兩半
and they'll rip this boat apart.
- 才不會呢      - 會的
- No, they won't.        - Yeah, they will.
爸爸 鯊魚會這樣嗎
Dad, will they?
- 是的 先生      - 閉嘴
- Yes, sir.        - Shut up.
我見過一群鯊魚像撕硬紙板一樣
You know, I've seen a school of sharks tear a boat to pieces
把船撕成碎片
like it was made of cardboard,
就因為有個小孩把創口貼扔進海裏了
because some kid threw a band-aid in the water.
對啊
Oh, yeah.
真的
Yeah, he did.
- 是啊      - 你才沒見過
- Oh, yeah.        - No, you didn't.
有時候避開它們的唯一方法
Sometimes the only way to keep them off is to throw the kid
就是直接把小孩扔進海裏來分散它們的注意力
directly in the ocean to distract them.
你閉嘴 鯊魚才不是成群結隊游來游去的
Shut up. Sharks don't even swim in schools.
他說鯊魚不是成群結隊游的
He says sharks don't swim in schools.
- 真是聰明的孩子      - 可不是嘛
- Smart kid.        - Yeah, he is.
聰明的孩子正是一大群鯊魚
A really smart kid is exactly the kind of quality meal
圍著船想找的美味晚餐
a humongous school of sharks is looking for when they're circling a boat.
李叔叔 你閉嘴
Oh, uncle Lee, shut up.
有魚上鉤了 上鉤了 上鉤了
Hey, you got a strike! Strike, strike, strike!
慢慢拉 慢慢拉 小心你的大拇指
Ease up on the drag, and watch your fuckin' thumb!
- 你有魚上鉤啦      - 別打我
- You got a strike now!        - Jesus! Don't hit me!
- 閉嘴啦 不許說髒話      - 他釣到魚啦
- No swearing!        - He got a strike!
- 慢慢來      - 我能搞定 我們能搞定
- Ease up on it.        - I got it! We got it!
專心開船 你忙你的去
Drive the boat! Mind your business!
- 你們要趕緊把魚鉤住      - 這是什麼魚
- You gotta get the hook in him.        - What kind of fish is it?
我們沒事 閉嘴 你忙你的去
We're fine! Shut up! Mind your business!
- 這是什麼魚      - 巨大的白色的
- What kind of fish is it?        - Great white.
- 一定是條大白魚      - 閉嘴
- It's gotta be a great white.        - Shut up!
或許是條梭子魚 誰知道呢
Or maybe a barracuda. Who knows?
這才不是鯊魚
It's not a shark!
- 加油 把它拉上來      - 才不是鯊魚呢
- Come on, pull him up!        - It's not a shark!
- 我們先別說話了...      - 快點
- Just stop talking!        - Come on!
那個怎麼會跟那些是連在一起的
How come that's connected to those?
沒有連在一起 只是看起來這樣而已
It's not connected, it just looks that way.
我來教你認認這些島嶼
I'm trying to teach you the islands.
這是那個有錢人買的島
That's the island the rich guy bought
所以其他人都不能在上面安家了
so no one else would put a house on it.
他就是這麼有錢
That's how rich he is.
貝克島 密瑟裏島
Baker island, Misery island.
我和你蘭迪阿姨就是在密瑟裏島結婚的
Misery island's where me and your aunt Randi got married.
- 哈嘍      - 嗨
- Hello?        - Yeah, hi.
蘇西 爸爸回來了
Suzy, daddy's home.
嗨 蘇西 爸爸回來了
Hi, Suzy. Daddy's home.
- 嗨 爸比      - 嗨 親愛的
- Hi, daddy.        - Hi, sweetheart.
要抱抱
Hug.
天哪 你要把我的脖子弄斷啦
Oh, Jesus Christ! You're breaking my neck!
李?
Lee?
來啦
Yeah, hang on.
- 嗨 玩得開心嗎      - 太開心了
- Hey. Did you have a good time?        - Yeah, really good.
- 你媽媽呢      - 他們剛走
- Where's your mother?        - They just left.
不是吧
Oh, no!
是啊 沒看到你 她也很難過
Yeah, she's sad to miss you too.
總有下一次的 你睡了嗎
Well, there's always next time. Did you get any sleep?
是啊 我媽媽在的時候她倒是挺安靜的
Oh, yeah, it's so restful when my mother's here.
真遺憾 嗨 小凱
Oh, too bad. Hi, Kary.
- 嗨 爸比      - 來
- Hi, daddy.        - Come here.
- 放我下來      - 我會把你放下來的 放輕鬆
- Put me down.        - I'm putting you down. Relax.
我只是想親親你 寶貝 好了
I'm just giving you a kiss. Honey, all right--
凱倫 凱倫
Karen! Karen!
- 我差點就要摔到你的頭了      - 天哪
- I almost dropped you on your head.        - Jesus.
我開了一家美發店
I'm making a hair salon.
那很棒哦
Oh, yeah? It's really good.
你想給我剪頭髮嗎
You wanna cut my hair?
只對女生開放 不好意思
It's just for girls. I'm sorry.
好吧 我理解 寶貝
That's all right. I understand, sweetheart.
我能看電視找找靈感嗎
Can I watch TV to get some ideas?
- 不行     - 好呀
- No.         - Yeah.
去吧
Go ahead.
走開
Get off.
噢 天吶
Oh, god.
你感覺怎麼樣
How you feeling?
好點了
Better.
- 是嗎      - 是啊
- Yeah?        - Yeah.
聽起來是好點了
You sound better.
所以你們真的會用漁具嗎
So did you guys actually use the fishing tackle?
是啊 那當然了
Oh, yeah.
小帕抓住一條巨大的藍魚 十八磅
Patty caught a humongous bluefish-- 18 pounds.
是嗎 那真是太厲害了
Oh, yeah? Well, that's awesome.
我從來沒見誰這麼開心過
Oh, I never seen anybody so happy in my whole life.
這裏真整潔呢
Oh, its nice in here.
你把這裏整理得乾乾淨淨 哇
You keep it nice. Wow.
- 真是持家能手啊      - 滾開
- What a homemaker.        - Fuck off.
好了 走開
All right. Get away from me.
別這樣
Stop it.
別 別這樣
Oh, don't. Stop.
拜託 我生病了
Please, I'm sick.
好了 走開
Okay. For real, get off of me.
- 嗨 斯坦尼      - 哦 天吶 別去吵他
- Hi, Stanny.        - Oh, god, let him alone.
- 你怎麼不哭了呢      - 我才剛把他哄睡著
- How come you're not crying?        - I just got him settled.
- 你幹嘛要把他哄睡著呢      - 李 別把他抱起來
- What did you get him settled for?        - Lee, don't pick him up.
如果他沒在哭 就見好就收吧
If he's not crying, leave well enough alone.
我和你媽媽當初就應該"見好就收"
Leave well enough alone. That's what me and your mommy
而不是結婚
should have done instead of getting married.
噢 閉嘴吧
Oh, shut up.
那麼世界上就不會有你了 也不會有你姐姐們了
Then you wouldn't be here. Your sisters wouldn't be here,
我就可以在自己的客廳安安靜靜地看球了
and I could watch the football game in my own living room with peace and quiet.
去死吧你
You know what? You can go fuck yourself.
噢 你好啊 小朋友
Oh, jeez Louise. Hey, kiddo.
天哪 你長得真帥 你知道嗎
Oh, my gosh. You're very handsome, you know that?
看到沒 我可沒把他弄哭
See that? I didn't make him cry.
抱起來 放回去
Up and down.
好的
Yeah.
他沒哭哦
He's not crying...
因為我知道怎麼搞定他
'Cause I know how to handle him.
喬呢 他怎麼樣
How is he? How's Joe?
挺好的 他還行吧
He's fine. You know, he's-- he's all right.
他還挺好的
Actually, he's doing all right.
你們的啤酒還夠喝嗎 你們這一天過得還好嗎
And you didn't run out of beer? You got through the day okay?
對啊 我們都很克制的
Oh, yeah. We were very temperate.
我不知道你們為什麼總要跑到那條該死的船上去
I don't know why you guys bother getting on the friggin' boat.
這是什麼意思 因為我們喜歡大海
What do you mean? We love the sea.
是嗎 你在海上喝了多少啤酒
Oh, yeah? How many beers did you have on the sea?
- 八瓶      - 八瓶?
- Eight.         - Eight?
是啊 七個小時
Yep, eight,
喝了八瓶 那...
over a seven-hour period, which--
哇 你可真行
wow, I am well impressed.
就是...
...is...
一小時1.1428572瓶啤酒
...1.1428572 beers an hour.
你難道沒有什麼別的能喝了嗎
It's like you didn't even have anything to drink at all.
我跟你說了 我已經在減量了
Yeah, I told you i was cutting down.
哦 天吶 不要 你想幹什麼
Oh, god, no. What do you think you're gonna do?
我想我應該洗個澡
I guess I'm gonna take a shower.
蘭迪 我發誓
Randi, I swear to god.
你應該看看他的表情
You should have seen his face.
太開心了
So happy.
就像我們帶女兒去坐旋轉木馬一樣
It was like when we took the girls on the merry-go-round.
那是純粹的開心
I mean, it was just pure happiness.
拜託 我病了
Oh, come on, I'm sick.
我病了 我真的
I'm sick. I'm really,
真的 不太舒服
really, deeply sick.
我快要不能呼吸了
It actually makes it hard to breathe.
他不在學校? 我以為學校放學...
He's not at school? I thought school left out--
- 我敢肯定他會...      - 什麼
- I'm pretty sure he would have--         - what?
抱歉 保羅 我的手機
I'm sorry, Paul, my phone is--
- 不好意思 能再說一遍嗎      - 沒事
- sorry. Say that again?         - That's all right.
我敢肯定他現在應該去參加冰球訓練了
I'm pretty sure he would have left for hockey practice by now.
他是冰球隊的?
He's on the hockey team?
是啊 而且他也打得很好
Yeah. Yeah, he's doing real well too.
喬怎麼樣 他沒事吧
Hey, how's Joe doing? He gonna be okay?
他沒事
Yeah, he's fine.
訓練在哪裏 在學校嗎
Where's the practice? Is it at the school?
不是的 他們在附近的格洛斯特訓練
No, they practice at Gloucester around.
- 他們在...      - 不好意思
- They practice in the--       - I'm sorry.
- 不在學校嗎      - 不在
- It's not at the school?        - No.
- 什麼 抱歉      - 是的
- What? I'm sorry.        - Yeah.
- 能聽見嗎      - 手機...
- Can you hear me?         - The phone is--
沒事 能聽見我說話嗎
that's all right. Can you hear me?
- 聽得見      - 在格洛斯特 好嗎
- Yes.         - It's at Gloucester, okay?
好 我知道了
Okay. I understand.
我們要打羅克波特隊 不過他們暫時領先
We play with the Rockport team, but they're the lead team.
好的 我知道了 謝謝你 保羅
Okay, I understand. Thank you, Paul.
好的 沒事 替我問候喬 好嗎
Yeah, sure thing. Give Joe my regards, all right?
- 我會的      - 怎麼了
- I will.        - What's up?
喬·錢德勒又進醫院了
Uh, Joe Chandler's in the hospital again.
- 真可怕      - 是啊
- Oh, how awful.        - Yeah.
- 電話裏的是誰      - 是李·錢德勒
- Who was on the phone?        - That was Lee Chandler.
- 李·錢德勒?      - 就是那個
- Lee Chandler?        - The very one.
嘿
Hey!
停下來
Knock it off!
錢德勒 給我住手
Chandler! Knock it off!
再有一次你就下場
One more time and you're out.
聽懂了嗎 錢德勒 再有一次
You understand that, Chandler? One more time.
- 我操      - 你說什麼
- Ah, fuck me.        - What's that?
- 操你媽的      - 好了 你出局了
- Fuck my fuckin' ass.        - All right, you're out.
- 錢德勒 去替補席待著      - 好吧
- Chandler, you're benched.        - All right.
好像我在乎似的
Ask me if I give a shit.
你說什麼
What was that?
教練 那是他叔叔
Coach, that's his uncle.
他爸爸肯定又進醫院了
His father must be in the hospital.
- 誰的爸爸 錢德勒爸爸嗎      - 他只會在...
Whose father, chandlers?        - Yeah, he only comes around--
他有心力衰竭
he's got congestive heart failure.
我是說帕特裏克的爸爸 不是帕特裏克
Patrick's dad, I mean, not-- not Patrick.
所以那是李·錢德勒 就是那個李·錢德勒?
So that's Lee Chandler.  The Lee Chandler, huh?
是啊 不過教練你知道那個故事是扯淡吧
Yeah, but coach, you know that story's bullshit, right?
完全是瞎扯 教練
Total bullshit, coach.
注意你們的用詞
You guys wanna watch the language?
- 對不起      - 對不起
- Sorry.        - Sorry.
好了 管好你們自己的事 好嗎
All right. Mind your own business for a little while, huh?
休息一下 喝點水
Let's take a break. Get a water.
所以 你爸爸怎麼樣了
So, uh, something going on with your dad?
他爸爸今天早上去世了
His father passed away this morning.
哦 天吶
Oh, jeez.
節哀順變
I'm sorry to hear that. I really am.
我...聽著 有事的話你儘管去
I, uh-- well, listen, do what you gotta do.
我真的覺得很難過
I, uh-- I feel terrible.
要不你去
Why don't you, uh--
你去把衣服換下來
all right, well, go in and change,
我們一會兒再說 好嗎
and we'll talk about it later, all right?
去吧 我在外面等你
Go ahead. I'll meet you outside.
- 好      - 好 謝謝
- All right.        - All right. Thank you.
好了 別看戲了
All right, show's over.
快過來 開始了
Come on, let's go.
- 你還好嗎      - 我的...
- You all right?        - Uh, my--
把你的球棍收起來 好嗎
take your sticks back, would you?
- 回頭見      - 好的
- Hey, I'll see you in there.        - Yeah.
- 我們一會兒再說吧      - 我過會兒打給你
- We'll talk, okay?        - I'll talk to you soon.
一會兒見 愛你
See you soon. I love you.
整隊
Line it up again.
快來 開始了
Come on, let's go.
我要回醫院去簽一些文件
I have to go to the hospital and sign some more papers.
你想看看他嗎
Do you wanna see him?
我不知道 為什麼
I don't know. Why?
他看起來什麼樣
What's he look like?
他看起來就像死了一樣
He looks like he's dead.
我是說 他看起來不像是睡著了之類的
I mean, he doesn't look like he's sleeping or anything.
看起來也不噁心
But he doesn't look gross, either.
我不知道
I don't know.
你也不是一定要去
Well, you know, you don't have to.
我想見見他
I wanted to see him.
但你可能不想在記憶裏留下那樣的畫面
Maybe you don't want that image in your memory.
我不...
I don't--
你自己決定
it's up to you.
你現在準備怎麼樣
What do you wanna do?
想讓我帶你回家嗎
You want me to take you home?
想讓我幫你決定嗎
Want me to decide for you?
我們走吧
Let's just go.
你他媽在幹嘛
What the fuck are you doing?
- 我說我們進去吧      - 不 你說的是"我們走吧"
- I just said let's go inside!        - No, you said let's just go,
- 然後你就下車了      - 我的意思是我們進去吧
- and then you get out of the car?        - I meant let's go inside.
- 你他媽怎麼回事      - 你有什麼問題
- What the matter with you?        - What's your problem?
- 我的問題就是我差點扯斷你他媽的腿      - 好好
- My problem is I could have ripped your fuckin' leg off!        - Okay, okay!
對不起 是我用錯了英語單詞
I'm sorry I misused the English language.
對不起 李叔叔
I'm sorry, uncle Lee.
我也跟你道歉 我只是嚇到了
I'm sorry, too. I just get scared.
好了 可以了 謝謝
Yeah, okay, thank you.
沒事
Of course.
你要按遙控門才開
You gotta hit the bleeper.
我沒有遙控
I don't have a bleeper.
我去開吧 要輸密碼
I'll do it. There's a code.
我可以叫幾個朋友過來嗎
Hey, is it okay if I invite some of my friends over?
- 我跟他們說了 我會打給他們      - 好的
- I told them I would call them.        - Go ahead.
我們可以叫點披薩嗎 因為這裏沒有什麼吃的
And can we get some pizza? 'Cause there's nothing to eat here.
好
Okay.
- 你喜歡什麼樣的      - 什麼樣的都行
- What kind would you like?        - Any kind is fine.
謝謝
Thank you.
至少他沒有受病痛折磨
At least he didn't suffer.
這對家人來說更難過 但是對本人來說是好事
It's worse for the family, but it's better for the person.
他真的是一個很好的人 帕特裏克
Well, he was a fuckin' great guy, Patrick, I'll tell you that.
毋庸置疑
That's for sure.
我還記得有一次他
Yeah, I remember this one time he--
他開船帶我們出海 大概六年級的時候
he took us out in the boat, like, in sixth grade.
是啊 我記得
Yeah, I remember that.
他讓我們穿上救生衣
He made us wear these life preservers.
然後我說
And I was like, you know,
"有什麼區別呢 錢德勒先生"
"what's the difference, Mr. Chandler?
"在這樣的天氣下 如果船沉了 我們怎麼都會死的"
The boat sinks in this weather, we're dead anyways."
- 是啊 我記得      - 然後他說
- Yeah, I remember that.        - Then he goes,
"救生衣的作用是 當你掉進水裏之後 鯊魚更容易看到你"
"the life jacket's to make it easy on the sharks once you go over."
真是個聰明的傢伙
Fuckin' smart ass, i swear to god.
是啊 他真的很喜歡拿鯊魚開玩笑
Yeah, he really liked those shark jokes.
- 有趣的人      - 他真有趣 哥們
- Funny guy.        - He was funny, man.
沒錯 他也很溫柔
Yeah, he was gentle too, you know?
跟他的兒子一樣
Like his son.
然後這個前星際飛船艦長
So there's this former starship captain, all right?
什麼 又聊星際迷航?
Jesus Christ! With the Star Trek again?
- 你他媽閉嘴      - 去你媽的 星際迷航爛透了
- Will you shut the fuck up?        - Fuck you. Star Trek sucks.
你這個該死的白癡
You fuckin' retard.
星際迷航是當代娛樂的經典核心
Star Trek's one of the classical pillars of modern entertainment.
- 是嗎      - 好嗎
- Oh yeah?        - All right?
那你來說說星際迷航 讓我好好聽聽
Tell me about Star Trek. Enlighten me, motherfucker.
- 我告訴你      - 我跟你做朋友多久了
- I'll tell you this--        - how long have I been friends with you?
- 你還好嗎 親愛的      - 我沒事
- How you doing, baby?        - I'm okay.
好了 夠了 好嗎 不就是星際迷航嘛
Enough is enough, okay? It's just Star Trek.
- 你好大的膽子 給我閉嘴      - 該死的星際迷航
- How dare you! Will you shut up?        - Fuck Star Trek.
所有你喜歡的經典科幻電影都是以星際迷航為基礎的
Every Sci-Fi classic film you like was based on Star Trek.
星際迷航就是扯淡
Star Trek's bullshit.
- 對吧 星際迷航...      - 星際迷航蠢極了
- Right? Start trek--  - Star Trek's retarded.
- 然後是公路勇士      - 蠢
- Then the road warrior.         - Retarded.
- 還有黑客帝國      - 又蠢又爛
- Then the matrix.         - Retarded and shit.
我超愛星際迷航
I love Star Trek!
- 哦 是嗎      - 你怎麼敢這麼說
- Oh, yeah, do you?        - How dare you?
你問帕特裏克 他也喜歡 他也喜歡
Ask Patrick. He loves 'em! He loves 'em!
- 好吧 帕特裏克 你覺得呢      - 來 問帕特裏克
- All right. Patrick, what do you think?        - Go ahead, ask Patrick.
不敢相信我們現在在討論星際迷航
I can't believe we're talking about Star Trek right now.
- 我喜歡星際迷航      - 謝謝你
- I like Star Trek.         - Thank you.
李叔叔
Hey, uncle Lee.
希爾薇可以在這裏過夜嗎
Is it okay if Silvie sleeps over?
爸爸都同意讓她過夜的
Dad always let her.
那你為什麼要問我呢
Then what are you asking me for?
不為什麼
No reason.
謝謝
Thanks.
以防萬一 我還是說一下
Uh, not that it would come up or anything,
她父母以為她在這過夜的時候是睡在樓下房間的
but her parents thinks she stays downstairs when she stays over.
所以萬一他們問起的話
So if it comes up for some reason,
你能告訴他們 她是睡在樓下的房間嗎
can you just say she stayed in the downstairs room?
- 我都不認識他們      - 你認識的
- I don't even know them.        - Yeah, you do.
米根夫婦 弗蘭克和帕特
It's the Mcganns. It's Frank and Pat Mcgann.
- 她是希爾薇·米根?      - 是的
- Oh, that's Silvie Mcgann?        - Yeah.
- 好吧      - 所以
- Okay.        - So...
你可以說她是睡樓下的嗎
Do you mind saying she stayed downstairs,
如果他們打電話過來之類的
like, if they call or something?
好
Okay.
我應該告訴你要用安全套嗎
Am I supposed to tell you to use a condom?
不用 我是說
No. I mean--
- 喬會這麼說嗎      - 不會
- is that what Joe would say?        - No.
我是說 沒錯 我們討論過這個話題
Well, I mean, yeah, we've had the discussion and everything.
- 所以...      - 那好
- So...       - Yeah, good.
是啊 如果我們太吵的話告訴我
Yeah, just let me know if we're making too much noise.
好
Okay.
你覺得我應該打給媽媽嗎
Um, do you think i should call my mom
告訴她爸爸的事
to tell her about dad?
- 不 是我我就不會 小帕      - 好吧
- No, I wouldn't, Patty.        - Yeah.
我是說 都沒人知道她在哪裏
I mean, uh, nobody even knows where she is.
是啊
Yeah.
是啊 我知道 我只是好奇你會怎麼想
Yeah, no, I was just curious what you thought.
不管怎麼樣... 晚安 李叔叔
Anyway, good night, uncle Lee.
晚安
Good night.
所以你要因為漏了個球生一晚上的氣嗎
Are you gonna sulk all night long because you dropped the goddamn ball?
- 我沒有生氣      - 閉嘴
- I'm not sulking.        - Oh, shut up.
如果你戴了該死的棒球手套的話 那個球也就不會掉了
If you'd use a goddamn baseball mitt, you wouldn't drop the fuckin' ball.
我不用手套 我不戴手套接得更好
I don't need a baseball mitt! I catch better without one.
閉嘴 閉嘴 埃莉斯
Hey, shut up. Hey, Elise!
該死 嘿
Oh, shit. Hey.
過來 李 你帶小帕上樓
Come on. Hey, Lee, you wanna take Patty upstairs
給他洗個澡好嗎
and get him washed up?
- 過來 孩子      - 去吧
- Come on, kid.        - Go on, now.
沒事的 我一會兒就上去
It'll be all right. I'll be up in a minute.
上樓吧 小帕 沒事的
Go on upstairs, Patty. Everything will be okay.
我覺得你失誤的那個球也挺好的
I thought it was wonderful how you dropped that ball.
- 好吧      - 我沒想讓你接到
- Okay.        - I didn't want you to catch it.
該死
Oh, shit.
走開
Go on.
操
Fuck's sake.
快他媽閉嘴
Shut the fuck up.
親愛的媽媽
我寫信是想告訴你
麻煩接 馬薩諸塞州貝弗利的加拉格爾殯儀館
Beverly, Massachusetts, Gallagher funeral home, please.
早上好
Morning.
嗨
Hi.
是的 你好 我叫李·錢德勒
Yes, hi, my name is Lee Chandler.
我的哥哥喬瑟夫·錢德勒現在在貝弗利醫院的太平間
My brother, Joseph Chandler, is at the Beverly Hospital morgue.
我在想
I'm wondering, uh,
商量後面的安排要找誰呢
who I need to talk to about making arrangements?
好的 謝謝
Okay, thank you.
是的
Yes.
是的 我剛剛跟...
Yes, I just spoke--
是的 我叫李·錢德勒
yes, my name is Lee Chandler.
我的哥哥正在貝弗利醫院的太平間
My brother is at the Beverly hospital morgue.
是的
Yes.
好
Okay.
我明白 我...
I understand, I'm--
我打電話來就是想知道
I'm calling to find out exactly what I need to do
我接下來具體應該怎麼安排
to make arrangements for the next step.
我知道了 好的 謝謝
I see. Okay, thank you.
能給我一張餐巾紙嗎
Can I have a napkin?
是的
Yes.
沒錯 但我不知道要怎麼把他的...
That's right, so-- but what do I gotta do to get his--
把他的遺體
to get his body over the--
不好意思 錢德勒先生 能別在帕特裏克面前說嗎
excuse me, Mr. Chandler, i don't think Patrick needs to be here for this.
這沒什麼
Don't-- I'm all right.
好的 我懂了
I understand.
為什麼運到曼徹斯特更貴
So why is it more to drive his body to Manchester?
因為要走七分鐘的高速
So you gotta take the highway for seven minutes,
所以就更貴了?
that's why it costs more?
那如果靈車走127號公路多少錢
Well, what does it cost for the hearse to take 127?
天啊 他還在計較這些
Jesus, like, that's his focus?
沒事
Jeez, I'm all right.
謝謝 李叔叔
Thanks, uncle Lee.
不用謝
You're welcome.
- 謝謝了 錢德勒先生      - 沒事
- Thanks, Mr. Chandler.        - You're welcome.
那麼
So...
我們先不說你上次爆粗口的事
We're gonna forget about the language.
也不提你上次動手打人的事
We're gonna forget about the fists.
但我想要你暫停幾天訓練
But I want you to take a few days off of practice.
你別來訓練了
I don't want you on the ice.
實話說 先生
Well, to tell you the honest truth, sir,
我可以把訓練當成分散注意力的方式
I could really use the distraction.
冰球不是一件讓你分散注意力的事
The ice is not a distraction.
當你在冰上時 你要全身心投入
When you're on the ice, you gotta be there.
所以 休息幾天吧
Okay, so take a couple days off,
然後我們再談
and we'll talk.
聽著
Listen.
我在像你這麼大時 我也失去了我爸
When I was your age, i lost my dad, too.
所以
So...
我明白你經歷了什麼
I know what you're-- you're goin' through.
如果你想來說說話
If you want to come in and talk,
想找個人傾訴一下
or want somebody to spill your guts to,
或者你想找個人發洩發洩
or throw the bull around,
我隨時歡迎你來
the door's open.
你介意我放點音樂嗎
You mind if i put some music on?
不介意
No.
你喜歡這群人？
do you like these guys?
主音吉他有點弱
The lead guitar is weak,
但其他都挺好
but otherwise they're pretty good.
在我聽起來 他們都一樣
Oh, they all sound the same to me.
我們去哪
Where are we goin'?
去見律師
Gotta go to the lawyer.
去幹嘛
What for?
我們要去看你爸的遺囑
To read your father's will.
我一定得在場嗎
Do I have to be there?
不一定 但我覺得你應該在場
I don't think so, but I think you're supposed to be.
你覺得他把船留給誰了
Who do you think he left the boat to?
我敢肯定他把什麼都留給你了
I'm sure he left you everything.
我不明白
I don't understand.
哪個部分不明白
Which, uh, part are you having trouble with?
我沒法當帕特裏克的監護人
Well, I can't be the guardian.
這...
Well... uh--
我是說 我做不到
I mean, I can't.
我自然是認為
Well, naturally, i-- I assumed Joe had
喬已經和你討論過這件事了
discussed all this with you.
沒有
No.
他沒說過
He didn't.
沒有
No.
呃...我
Uh, i-- i--
不得不說 我還真有些吃驚了
sorry, I have to say, I'm somewhat taken aback.
他不能和我住一起 我只有一個房間
He can't live with me. I live in one room.
但喬提供了帕特裏克之後的生活所需
Well, but Joe has provided for Patrick's upkeep.
食物啊 衣服啊等等
Food, clothes, etcetera.
房子和船都是他的
And the house and the boat are owned outright.
但我總不能在他18歲前
I can't commute from Boston every day
天天從波斯頓往這來回跑吧
until he turns 18.
我想也許你可以換個地方住
I think the idea was that you would relocate.
換去哪
R-- relocate to where?
你看看這寫的
Well, you look-- - here?
你可以看得出來 你哥哥
Well, as you can see, your brother
把一切都安排得非常仔細
worked everything out extremely carefully.
- 但是他不可能      - 是的
- But he can't have--        - yes.
他不可能是那個意思
He can't have meant that.
他還拿出五千美元
Uh, he's allowed up to $5,000
作為你的搬家費
to pay for moving expenses.
你還有一小筆錢
And there's, uh-- there's also a small amount
可以支取
set aside for, uh, you know,
作為補貼
for you to draw from-- as personal income.
在你搬來之後
while you settle in.
當然是在你接受的前提下
I mean, assuming that you accept.
那唐尼叔叔和特蕾莎嬸嬸呢
What about my uncle Donny and aunt Teresa?
喬覺得帕特裏克和他們
Joe didn't feel that Patrick really had any special relationship
- 沒什麼深厚的感情      - 我不明白
- or feeling about them--        - I don't understand.
我想你應該知道
And now, as I think you know,
他們現在好像搬去威斯康星州了
they've moved out to Wisconsin, I believe.
明尼蘇達
Minnesota.
- 是明尼蘇達      －明尼蘇達州的明尼通卡
- Minnesota.        - Minnetonka, Minnesota.
是的
That's right.
我印象裏你這些年在這待了不少時間
It was my impression that you'd spent a lot of time here over the years.
我只是個過來幫個忙
I was just the back up.
自從我爸照顧不了小帕之後
I came up here to look after Patty, yeah,
喬住院的時候我會過來照顧小帕
if Joe was in the hospital after my father couldn't do it,
但我們...
but we--
本來應該是唐尼來的
it was supposed to be Donny.
我只是來幫個忙
I'm just the back up.
我只能說 我 我
Well, i-- I can just repeat that I'm-- I'm...
真沒想到喬沒跟你說這件事
Astonished that Joe didn't run this by you,
畢竟他是個很周到的人
thorough as he was.
那是因為他知道問了我 我會怎麼說
Yeah, 'cause he knew what I would say if he would have asked.
運氣 你這是運氣球
Once! It was once!
運氣而已 就這麼一次
Oh, one time nothin'. It's nothin' but one time.
小心這邊的球
Stay out of this quadrant,
不然我會把你打哭
and you won't go home in tears.
好啊
All right.
嘿
Hey!
給我小點聲音 你們這些蠢豬
You wanna keep it down, you fuckin' morons?
我的孩子們還在睡覺呢
My kids are sleepin'.
我很抱歉 我真心的 我沒想到我們這麼吵
I'm so sorry. I am-- I didn't think we were that loud.
李 能請你把這些混蛋
Lee. You wanna get these fuckin' pinheads
趕出我家嗎
out of my house, please?
好 我會的
Yeah, I do.
蘭迪 我會的
Randi, I really do.
她不能這樣跟我們說話
She can't talk to us that way.
是啊
Yeah.
嘿
Hey!
我可沒跟你們開玩笑
I'm not fuckin' around!
這他媽的都凌晨兩點了
It's 2:00 in the fuckin' morning.
快讓這群混蛋穿好衣服
Get these fuckin' assholes dressed,
然後他媽滾出去
and get 'em the fuck out of here!
我們都穿得好好的呢
We are dressed.
她不是故意的 她一會兒會道歉的
She didn't mean it. She'll apologize later.
得走了 哥們
Gotta get out of here, man.
- 回見      - 回見
- See ya later.        - Right on.
李
Lee.
- 謝了 哥們 保重      - 好
- Thanks, bro. Take care!        - All right!
- 幫我們向蘭迪道個歉      - 晚安
- Tell Randi we're sorry.        - Good night!
- 別酒後駕駛      - 真不好意思
- Don't drink and drive.        - We're so sorry!
看見木星了嗎
You see Jupiter?
喂 湯米
Hey, Tommy!
晚安 喬
Good night, Joe!
抱歉啊
Sorry again!
去吧 那是木星 你個白癡
Go ahead. It's Jupiter, you fuckin' idiot.
看見北極星了嗎
Look at, there's the north star right there.
- 就在那      - 在哪
- Right there.        - Where?
就在正北方
It's-- it's due north.
我早上會打掃乾淨的
I'll clean up in the morning.
你能看見木星? 混蛋
You see Jupiter, you fuckin' asshole?
別這樣
Come on.
去你的
Fuck you.
別這樣
Come on.
李
Lee.
李 沒人能體會你經歷了什麼
Lee, nobody can appreciate what you've been through.
如果我能這麼說的話
If I can say that.
如果你真的覺得你做不到
And if you really feel like you can't take this on,
那是...
well, that's-- that's--
那也是你的權利
you know, that's your right.
- 顯而易見      - 那誰來管他
- Obviously.        - So who would get him?
帕特裏克 來罐蘇打或別的什麼嗎
Patrick, can I get you a can of soda or anything?
不用了 謝謝你
No, thank you.
我不知道帕特裏克的母親現在怎麼樣了
Well, I don't know what's happening with Patrick's mother.
- 不行      - 我不知道她在哪
- No.        - I'm not sure where she is,
- 也不知道她現在是什麼情況      - 不行
- or what kind of condition she's in.        - No.
我們不能那麼做
We can't do that.
天啊 不要 天啊
God, no! Oh, god!
弗雷德 弗雷德 我的孩子還在裏面
Fred! Fred! My kids are in there!
我的孩子還在裏面
My kids are in there!
天啊 我的天啊
God! Oh, god!
我要進去
I gotta go in there.
這樣吧 李
Look, Lee.
那要不你...
Why don't you just--
我們再聯繫吧
I'm gonna-- I'll be in touch.
我在這等你
Um, I'm here.
我們在聚會 玩得挺嗨
Well, we were partying pretty hard.
喝啤酒
And there was beer.
有人還帶了大麻煙來
And someone was passin' around a joint,
還有可卡因
and there was cocaine.
可卡因？
Cocaine?
是的
Yes.
接著說
Okay, go ahead.
總之 我們的臥室在樓下
Uh, anyway, our bedroom is in the downstairs,
孩子們睡在樓上
and the kids sleep upstairs,
兩點的時候蘭迪把所有人都趕走了
so Randi makes everyone leave around 2:00.
也可能是三點
Or 3 A.M.
然後
And then...
她就回去睡覺了
She goes back to bed.
我到樓上看了看孩子們
So I go upstairs to check on the kids,
樓上太他媽冷了
and it's fuckin' freezin' upstairs,
但我不能開中央暖氣
but I can't use the central heat
因為蘭迪會鼻竇發乾
'cause it dries out randi's sinuses,
然後就會頭疼得很厲害
and gives her really bad headaches.
於是我下了樓 在壁爐裏生了火
So I go downstairs and i put a fire in the fireplace,
然後坐下來看電視
and sit down and watch TV,
可是發現啤酒沒了
but there's no more beer.
我還是冷得直跺腳
I'm still jumpin' around like... a jackrabbit,
所以我在火裏又加了幾塊柴火
so I put a couple of fire logs in the fire,
這樣就能趁我出門的時候把家裏弄暖和點了
and i-- just to warm up the house while I was gone.
然後我去了趟小超市
And then i-- I'm goin' to the mini mart,
但是我喝得太醉了 所以不想開車
but I'm too wasted and i don't want to drive.
所以我走路過去 來回各二十分鐘
So I walk, it's about 20 minutes each way.
大概走到半路時
I'm about halfway there,
我不記得我有沒有把爐罩蓋在爐子上了
and I can't remember if I put a screen on the fireplace.
但我想應該沒事
I figure it's okay.
於是就繼續往商店走了
So I just keep goin' to the store.
就這樣了
And, uh, that's it.
應該是有一塊木頭滾到了地上
Log must have rolled out onto the floor.
消防員說他們把蘭迪救出來了
Uh, fireman said they pulled Randi out.
她昏倒在樓下
She passed out downstairs.
然後爐子爆了
and then the furnace blew,
他們沒法再進去一趟了
and they couldn't go back in again.
我就記得這麼多了
That's all I remember.
好的 李 暫時就這樣吧
Okay, Lee, that's all for now.
如果還有什麼事要問你的話
We'll-- we'll call you if anything else comes up
我們會打電話給你的
we want to ask you about.
如果法醫證實你說了的話
Assuming the forensics bear you out,
我想應該是沒問題
which I'm assuming they will.
什麼 這就完了？
So, uh, that's it?
聽著 李 昨晚你犯了一個
Look, Lee, you made a horrible mistake.
所有人都可能會犯的致命錯誤
Like a million other people did last night.
但我們不會因此把你釘上十字架
Not gonna crucify you.
忘記把爐罩放回爐子裏並不是罪
It's not a crime to forget to put the screen on the fireplace.
呃 我是說
Well, I mean, you know,
那我能走了？
so I can go?
除非有什麼新情況 現在你可以走了
Well, if something comes up we don't already know about, yeah.
有人來接你回家嗎
You got anyone to give you a ride back home?
喬來了嗎 你爸爸來了嗎
Is Joe here? Is your dad here?
來了
Yeah.
- 抱歉      - 那好
- Sorry.        - Okay.
孩子
Son!
放下槍 放下槍
Put it down. Put it down!
按在地上 按在地上
Get on the ground. Get on the ground.
- 拜託      - 冷靜點 冷靜點
- Ah, please!        - Settle down. Settle down.
- 拿手銬來      - 別起來
- We need some cuffs right now.        - Stay down.
- 別起來      - 按住 把他按在地上
- Stay down.        - Down, down, get him down.
好了 我們走吧
All right, let's go.
再見
Bye.
我們去哪 孤兒院嗎
Where we goin', to the orphanage?
- 閉嘴      - 我幹嘛了我
- Shut up.        - What the hell did I do?
安靜一會
Just be quiet.
我們還有很多事要做
All right, we got a lot to do.
- 船怎麼辦      - 我們可以和喬治討論這件事
- What about the boat?        - We can talk to George about it.
如果沒人要用的話
There's no use hangin' onto it
- 也沒必要留著它了      - 我會用的
- if no one's gonna use it.        - I'm gonna use it.
- 它還得經常保養      - 我在保養
- It's gotta be maintained.        - I'm maintaining it.
- 我以後都會保養它的      - 你自己一個人可做不了
- I'm gonna maintain it.        - You can't maintain it by yourself.
為什麼不行 它現在是我的船了 不是嗎
Why not? It's my boat now, isn't it?
因為你還是個未成年人 你無法單獨所有
'Cause you're a minor, you can't take it out alone.
我是托管人
I'm-- I'm the trustee.
- 我得去給你買單      -  托管人是什麼意思
- I gotta make the payments--        - what does trustee mean?
跟進所有的檢查
I gotta keep up the inspections.
意思是你的所有事情都由我來負責直到...
It means I'm in charge of handling everything for you until--
是不是說我不想讓你賣 你也可以賣
does that mean you're allowed to sell the boat if I don't want you to?
直到你十八歲成年
Until you turn 18. I don't know.
我肯定會這麼考慮的
I'll definitely consider it.
- 想都別想      - 別對你自己太自信了
- No fuckin' way.        - You're so goddamn sure of yourself.
- 我們沒人去經營它 你才十六歲      - 我今年可以拿到執照
- There's no one to run it. You're 16 years old.        - I get my license this year.
那又怎麼樣 你還是個未成年人
Doesn't matter, you're still a minor.
你不能獨自經營商業用船
You can't run a commercial vessel by yourself.
而且這還是很大一筆開銷 我才是那個付錢的人
Meanwhile, it's a big fuckin' expense, and I'm the one that's gotta manage it,
- 而且我都沒法待在這裏      - 誰他媽在乎你在哪
- and I'm not gonna be here.        - Who gives a fuck where you are?
小帕 我對天發誓我會打爆你的頭
Patty, I swear to god, I'm gonna knock your fuckin' block off.
- 真是個好爸爸      - 什麼 你說什麼
- Great parenting.        - What? What'd you say?
- 我說 真是個好爸爸      - 我操
- I said great parenting.        - Fuck you!
管好你自己的事 你個混球
Mind your fuckin' business, you fuckin' asshole!
你要衝我臉上來一拳嗎
You're gonna smash me in the face.
嘿 沒事了 沒事了 沒事了
Hey, it's okay, it's okay, it's okay.
- 沒事了 沒事了      - 你要衝我臉上來一拳?
- It's okay, it's okay.        - You want me to smash your fuckin' face,
- 你個混球      - 沒事了 沒事了
- you fuckin' asshole.        - It's okay. It's okay.
謝謝 謝謝 沒事了
Thank you. Thank you. It's okay.
李叔叔 你徹底發瘋嗎
Uncle Lee, are you fundamentally unsound?
給我他媽的上車
Get in the fuckin' car.
你不開門我可沒法照做
Can't obey your orders until you unlock the door.
閉上你的嘴
Shut up.
雖然這個發動機一時半會還壞不了
It's not like the motor's gonna die tomorrow,
但喬說它就像個混蛋一樣總是掉鏈子
but Joe said it keeps breakin' down like a son of a bitch.
嗯 但我們還是要看一下
Yeah, but we were gonna take a look--
雖然我們有那麼一筆錢
see, there's an allotment of some kind, but--
這個週末要看一下
take a look this weekend.
但這事還不一定
Things are a little bit up in the air.
不 我會負責的
No, i-- I can take care of it
做做日常保養什麼的
as far as the general maintenance is concerned,
但發動機總有一天會壞的
but that motor's gonna go at some point.
我會負責的
I'm taking care of it.
沒有留出來買新發動機的錢
There's no allotment for a new motor.
除非...喬治 你認識誰想要把它買走的嗎
Unless, George, you know someone who wants to buy it.
等一下 我不賣
Wait a second, I'm not selling it.
反正我們要去波士頓的
We're gonna be in Boston, anyway.
什麼
What?!
我什麼時候得待在波士頓了
Since when are we supposed to be in Boston?
別一驚一乍的
Just take it easy.
不管你怎麼決定的
Well, whatever you decide,
光把它擱在那就能擱到你破產
it's gonna bleed you dry just sittin' here.
我們還沒決定到底要怎麼辦
Well, we don't know exactly what we're doin'.
你知道的 他隨時可以過來住我們這
Well, you know, he can always stay with us
你如果他想週末來玩玩的話
if he wants to come up weekends.
你想當他的監護人嗎
Do you want to be his guardian?
- 那個...我們已經      - 他又不想當我的監護人
- Well, we already--        - he doesn't want to be my guardian,
我的天啊
for Christ sakes.
- 這段時間有些孩子該離開家了      - 你去他家看過嗎
- We're tryin' to lose some kids at this point.        - Have you seen his house?
- 是啊      - 沒去過 我們現在要釐清這些雜事
- Yeah.        - No, we're tryin' to work out the logistics,
- 我也不知道      - 我們家確實很擠
- so I don't know--        - we're jammed in there pretty good,
- 但是我們...      - 天吶 能別說了嗎
- but we--        - Jesus Christ, will you stop?
但我們家的沙發總會留給他 只要他願意 隨時都可以
We've always got a sofa for him any time he wants.
- 喬治      - 你明白的 對吧
- George--        - you know that, right?
沒事 我明白
That's all right, i know-- I know that.
- 我們隨時都歡迎他      - 我明白
- He's welcome any time.        - I understand.
我明白 謝謝你
I-- I know. Thank you.
你腦子壞了嗎
Are you brain damaged?
你不能和別人這麼說
You can't just talk to people like that.
你不想當我的監護人 這對我來說沒什麼
You don't want to be my guardian, that's fine with me.
不是這個問題 這只是些雜事
It's not that, it's just the logistics.
我得理理清楚 我發誓
I've just gotta work it all out, i swear.
怎麼做 把我送去明尼蘇達州瓦卡湯卡
How? My takin' me to wonkatonka, Minnesota,
- 唐尼叔叔那裏?      - 是明尼通卡
- with uncle Donny?        - Minnetonka.
- 明尼蘇達的明尼通卡      - 好吧 明尼蘇達的明尼通卡
- Minnetonka, Minnesota.        - Okay, minnetonka, Minnesota.
有什麼區別
Same difference.
那我媽不行嗎
What about my mother?
法官不會把你給她
The judge would never let that happen.
再說沒人知道她在哪
And anyway, no one even knows where she is.
我知道
I do.
她在康涅狄格州
She's in Connecticut.
至少去年是在那裏
At least she was last year.
你什麼時候知道的
Since when do you know that?
她去年給我發郵件了
Well, she emailed me last year,
所以我給她回信了
so I emailed her back.
你知道嗎 郵件
You know email?
你爸知道你跟她還有聯繫嗎
Did your father know you were in touch with her?
你在開玩笑嗎
Are you kidding?
我們能邊走邊說嗎 我快凍死了
Can we walk? I'm freezing.
- 關於她 我只知道...      - 我知道 我知道 我知道
- All I know is--        - I know, I know, I know.
她是個酒鬼 是個瘋子
She's a drunk, she's insane,
讓狗在地板上拉屎
she let the dog shit on the floor.
這是你爸
It's the last thing that your father
最不願意看到的
ever would have wanted.
你什麼時候開始在乎他的想法了
Oh! Oh, like suddenly you care what he would have wanted.
現在去哪
Where to now?
- 殯儀館      - 好極了
- The funeral parlor.        - Great.
哇 我們這是去哪
Whoa, whoa, whoa, where are we--where are we goin'?
他在比弗利的殯儀館
He's in Beverly.
曼徹斯特連殯儀館都沒有？
There's no funeral homes in Manchester?
沒有
Nope.
墓碑會在這
The cemetery's here.
讓我們把這事給完成了吧
Let's just get this done.
冬天有很多人取南方避寒
Down south, we got a lot of snowbirds.
年初 人們從北邊往南邊走
Early in the year, people from the north head down there,
有人就在那裏過世了 雖然不是那邊的人
they die down there, they're not from the area.
那跟我們有什麼關係
What do they even like about us?
- 都是為愛的人辦理後事      - 是啊
- Makin' arrangements for a loved one.        - Right.
很多時候 人們來我們這裏
A lot of times, people are comin' in,
- 這可以說是他們最不喜歡的事了      - 沒錯
- last thing they had on their mind.        - Right.
有時候 我發現雖然家庭內部不太和諧
Sometimes I find there's dysfunction in the family still,
但通常人們還是會出席葬禮的
somehow people come together. You know?
那傢伙嚴肅又憂鬱的樣子是怎麼回事
Dude, what is with that guy and the big serious and somber act?
我不知道
I don't know.
說真的 難道他意識不到
No, but seriously, does he not realize
大家都知道他每天都這麼做嗎
that people know he does this every single day?
我不知道
I don't know.
我們為什麼不能安葬他
Why can't we bury him?
天氣太冷 地面太硬了
Too cold. The ground is too hard.
要到春天再下葬
They'll bury him in the spring.
所以在那之前 他們會拿他怎麼樣
So what do they do with him until then?
把他放在冰櫃裏
Put him in a freezer.
你說真的嗎
Are you serious?
沒錯
Yes.
這可真嚇到我了
That really freaks me out.
這沒什麼的
It doesn't matter.
等等
Wait a minute.
我想我把車停在另一邊了 抱歉
I think I parked the car the other way. Sorry.
那用小型蒸汽挖土機行嗎
What about one of those mini steam shovels?
什麼
What?
有一次我在紐黑文的墓園
I once saw one of those mini steam shovels
見過一種小型蒸汽挖土機
one time in a graveyard in New Haven.
兩秒鐘就能挖出一個完整的坑
It's like a perfect little hole in about two seconds.
我不知道要去哪裏弄一把來
Well, I don't really know how to get a hold of one
也不知道要花多少錢
or how much it would cost.
我們不能考慮一下嗎
Why can't we just look into it?
你不能在羅斯代爾歷史公墓
Because you can't use heavy equipment
使用重型設備
in the historic rosedale cemetery.
為什麼不能
Why not?
因為有很多重要人物
Because there are very important people
埋葬在那裏
who are buried there,
他們的子孫不想讓蒸汽挖土機
and their descendants don't want steam shovels
在他們的墓地上震動
vibrating over their dead bodies.
那為什麼我們不能換個地方下葬
Well, why can't we just bury him someplace else?
因為喬買的就是這個地方
Because that's the plot that Joe bought.
別問我為什麼
Don't ask me why.
但如果你想要有其它安排
But if you want to make some other arrangements,
你想另找地方安葬他
you want to find someplace else to bury him,
你想和殯葬人員談
you want to talk to the mortician,
你想打電話給神聖之心
and you want to call up sacred heart
和馬丁神父談話
and talk to father Martin
弄明白這些要花多少錢
and find out how much that's gonna cost
然後安排這一切的話
and make all those arrangements,
隨你來 否則你就別管
be my guest. Otherwise, let's just leave it.
我只是不想讓他待在冰櫃裏
I just don't like him being in a freezer.
是啊
Yeah.
我也不想
I don't like it, either,
但那不是他 他已經離開了
but it isn't him because he's gone.
那只是他的遺體
It's just his body.
我只想說 我有點被嚇壞了
I'm just saying it kind of freaks me out.
媽的 我到底把這該死的車停在哪裏了
Oh, god damn it, where did I park the car?
我不知道 但願你能想起來
Yeah, I don't know, but i wish you'd figure it out
因為我現在快被凍死了
because I'm freezing my ass off.
你沒件像樣的冬衣嗎
You don't have a normal winter coat?
有啊 我有的
Yeah. Yeah, I do.
你為什麼不戴雙能套住手指的手套
Why don't you wear gloves with the real fingers on them?
媽的
Oh, god, fuck.
操 我他媽到底把這該死的車停在哪裏了
Oh, fuck, where did I park this motherfucking car?
真他媽冷
God damn, it's cold.
怎麼 你的冬季夾克不保暖嗎
Why? What's the matter with your winter jacket?
- 你認真的嗎 小帕      - 快把暖氣打開
- Seriously, Patty?        - Just turn the heat on.
已經開了
It's on already.
那再開大一點
Well, turn it up a little.
已經開到最大了
It's all the way up.
它在朝我吹冷氣呢
It's blowing freezing air on me.
等一分鐘就會暖和起來
It just needs a minute to warm up.
你什麼時候買的這破車 1928年嗎
What year did you get this thing, 1928?
隨車附贈的那匹馬在哪呢
Where's the horse that goes with this fucking car?
沒準它還能朝我們吹點熱氣
Maybe he can breathe on us.
小帕 別逼我
Patty, I swear to god.
我知道 怎麼不把我爸在這破車上
I know. Why don't we keep my dad in here
放三個月
for the next three months?
還能給你省一大筆錢
You'd save a fucking fortune.
冰櫃的事你能閉嘴嗎
Would you shut the fuck up about the freezer?
你想讓我就被一個葬禮和那幾個殯儀員
Want me to have a nervous breakdown
弄到精神崩潰嗎
because there's undertakers and a funeral?
- 誰在乎      - 不 我沒這麼想
- Who cares?        - No. I don't.
好了 暖和一點了
Okay, it's getting warmer.
我有個樂隊排練 你能送我回家
I got band practice. Can you drive me home
好讓我拿上東西
so I can get my stuff
然後再送我去我女朋友家嗎
and take me over to my girlfriend's house?
當然
Sure.
這是來過家裏的那個女孩嗎
This the same girl who was over at the house?
不 那是希爾薇 這是桑迪
No. That was Sylvie, and this is Sandy.
她們都不知道對方的存在
They don't know about each other,
所以什麼都別說
so, uh, please don't say anything
以防被拆穿
in case it comes up.
我不會說
I won't.
你真的和這兩個女孩都上過床嗎
Do you actually have sex with these girls?
難道蓋上棉被純聊天嗎
We don't just play computer games.
兩個都有嗎
With both of them?
桑迪的媽媽在
Well, with Sandy's mom here,
所以有點不方便 就像搞地下活動一樣
it's sort of, uh, strictly just like basement business.
這是什麼意思
What does that mean?
意思是我正在想辦法
It means I'm working on it.
停 奧托 你怎麼回事
Stop. Otto, man, what are you doing?
我怎麼了
What did I do?
你慢太多了 兄弟
You're way behind, man.
不 我沒有
No, I'm not.
你有點沒跟上 奧托
You're a little behind, Otto.
你應該緊跟貝斯來 奧托
You got to stay with the bass, Otto.
別這樣 兄弟 你跟緊我 好嗎
Come on, man, just stay with me, all right?
- 開始吧     - 好吧 抱歉
- Let's go.        - All right, I'm sorry.
沒事 來吧
All right. Yeah. Come on.
沒事
It's all right.
來吧 開始
Come on, let's go.
- 好了 大伙      - 再來一遍
- All right, guys.        - Let's go again.
奧托 你可以了嗎
Otto, you good?
- 準備好了嗎 哥們      - 來吧 親愛的
- You good, buddy?        - Let's go, baby.
我們是 響徹雲霄
We are Stentorian.
一 二 三
1 2 3
嗨 你是李嗎
Hi. Are you Lee?
我是吉爾 桑迪的媽媽
I'm Jill, Sandy's mom.
我想他們的排練快結束了
I think they're wrapping up.
你想進去喝杯啤酒什麼的嗎
You want to come inside and have a beer or something?
不用了 謝謝
It's all right. Thank you.
我想向你表達我對喬的悼念之情
I wanted to offer my condolences about Joe.
他是個很好的人
He was a terrific guy.
像他那樣的好人現在已經很少了
There's not too many like him.
他是個很棒的父親
He was a wonderful father.
謝謝你
Thank you.
我正想問帕特裏克
I was-- I was going to ask Patrick
要不要留下來吃飯
if he wants to stay for supper,
如果你同意的話
if that's okay with you.
你想一起吃嗎 我飯菜做太多了
You want to join us? I made way too much.
沒事
That's all right.
我一會兒再回來接他
I'll just come back and get him.
什麼時候 我什麼時候過來
What time... What time should I come back?
我不知道 九點 或者九點半吧
Oh, I don't know. 9, 9:30.
他們要一起寫作業 應該吧
They're going to do their homework together, supposedly.
哈 哈 哈
Ha ha ha.
好吧 我九點半再過來
All right. I'll come back at 9:30.
好吧 要是你十分鐘之內改主意了
Okay. When you change your mind in the next ten minutes,
我們就在屋裏
we're right inside.
好的 謝謝
Okay. Thanks.
老天 這個要怎麼解開
Jesus Christ, how do you unbuckle this?
我手指都要蹭破皮了
I'm scraping the skin off my knuckles.
停下 把你的手拿出來
Hold on. Just take your hand out.
能請你
Would you please
把手從我下面挪開嗎
just take your hand out of my cunt?
好 好
Okay. Okay.
我們現在要脫褲子嗎
Oh, are we taking our pants off?
我是要脫褲子了
I'm taking my pants off.
我不知道你在幹嘛
I don't know what you're doing.
那我也要脫褲子
I'm taking my pants off.
快點
Come on.
你得先脫掉你的鞋子
You got to take your show off first.
- 天吶      - 我在脫呢
- Jesus.        - I'm-- I'm trying.
孩子們 快下來吃飯了
Hey, kids, come on, have some dinner.
謝謝 媽 我們馬上就下來
Thanks, mom. We'll be right down.
謝謝 吉爾 馬上
Thanks, Jill. One second.
我得先退出
I just got to log off.
你能別演了嗎 她又不是弱智
Would you shut up? She's not retarded.
你為什麼要和我過不去
Why are you picking on me?
我沒有和你過不去
I'm not picking on you.
你在給我惹麻煩
You'll get me in trouble.
我沒有給你惹麻煩
I'm not going to get in trouble.
那你是想做什麼
What are you trying to do?
數學作業做得怎麼樣了
How's the math homework?
挺好的
It's good.
挺失敗的
Very frustrating.
很好
Good.
那些算法真是折磨死人
Those algorithms are a bitch.
這個真的很好吃 吉爾
This is really good, Jill.
- 謝謝你 帕特裏克      - 這是...
- Thank you, Patrick.        - Is this a--
這是自製培根意面醬嗎
this is a homemade carbonara sauce?
天了 閉嘴吧
Jesus, shut up.
不是
No.
你不說我還以為是呢
You could have fooled me.
老天
Jesus.
什麼 怎麼了
What? What?
你真是個馬屁精
You're such a kiss-ass.
- 桑迪      - 怎麼了
- Sandy!        - What,
我不就是誇你媽的廚藝好嗎
because I appreciate your mother's cooking?
- 晚安      - 晚安
- Good night.        - Good night.
你都不問我發生了什麼嗎
Aren't you going to ask what happened?
- 我不想知道      - 我猜也不想
- I don't want to know.        - Guess not.
加把勁啊
Come on.
你好
Hello.
你好 是李嗎
Hello. Lee?
我是蘭迪
It's Randi.
- 你好      - 是 抱歉 我在
- Hello?         - Yeah. Sorry. I'm here.
- 你好 你怎麼樣      - 我很好 你好嗎
- Hi. How are you?        - Okay. How are you?
- 挺好的      - 好吧
- Good.        - Good.
我打來是因為
I was just calling--
喬治告訴了我喬的事情
George  told me about Joe,
我只想打來說聲節哀順變
and I just wanted to call  and say I'm sorry.
我希望你不介意我打來
I hope you don't mind  me calling.
不會 沒事 謝謝你
No. It's fine. Thank you.
我不介意 你怎麼樣
I don't mind. How are you?
我現在挺難過的
Not so good right now.
我想我們都預料到這件事
I guess we should have seen it coming,
但是 還是有點讓人不敢相信
but it's still hard to believe.
- 是啊      - 是啊
- Yeah.        - Yeah.
- 帕特裏克怎麼樣      - 他還好
- How's Patrick doing?        - He's good.
只是表面上看起來吧
Beyond the obvious,  obviously.
他還好 他沒事 我也不知道
He's okay. He's fine. I don't know.
不過你也知道 孩子都很難懂
You know how kids are. It's hard to tell.
他不太對我敞開心扉
He doesn't really open up with me,
但他看起來沒事 他有一大群朋友
but he seems fine. He's got a lot of friends.
- 那很好      - 是的
- Oh, well, that's good.         - Yeah, it is.
所以 我不知道你有沒有準備好舉行葬禮
So I don't know if you'd planned a service yet,
但我想問 要是你不介意的話
but I was also going to ask,  if you wouldn't mind,
我想去參加葬禮 可以嗎
I'd like to be there if it's okay with you.
沒事 我不介意
Yeah, it's fine. I don't mind.
那好 謝謝你
Okay, okay. Thank you.
這對我來說意義重大
It would mean a lot to me.
沒事 你應該來的
No, you should come.
我會通知你時間
I'll let you know when it's going to be.
謝謝你
Thank you.
所以我能問你
So can I ask, uh...
你還好嗎
How are you?
我不知道 你還好嗎
I don't know. How are you?
我不知道
I don't know.
我們都還挺好
We're doing pretty well.
我想我應該告訴你
I should probably tell you.
我要當...
I'm going to be a--
其實 我懷孕了
actually,  I'm-- I'm pregnant.
- 是嗎      - 是啊
- Oh, yeah?        - Yeah.
而且 就快要生了
You know, like, ready to pop.
我還真不知道
Oh, I didn't know that.
我不知道是不是應該和你說
Uh, I didn't know if I should tell you,
但是
but...
沒事 沒關係 祝賀你
No, it's fine. Congratulations.
謝謝你  你見到我的時候
Thank you. You would probably deduce it for yourself
也能看出來
when you see me.
是啊
Yeah.
所以
So, uh, you know,
我只是想說 那個...
I just wanted to say,  you know--
我想說 對不起
actually, uh, i-- oh, sorry.
我不是有意掛你電話 我還有事
I didn't mean to cut you off. I just got to go.
沒事 我只想打來確認一下
I just wanted to make  sure it's okay
我和喬希是不是方便參加葬禮
if me and Josh come to the funeral.
- 完全沒問題      - 謝謝你 李
- It's totally okay.        - Thank you, Lee.
好的 上帝保佑
Okay. God bless.
- 再會      - 再見
- So long.        - Bye.
你在開玩笑嗎 我從來都沒去過波士頓
Are you kidding me? I've never even been to Boston.
哦 那挺好的 你和帕特裏克
Oh, it's great, you and Patrick.
是啊
Oh, yeah.
所以 你還好嗎
So how are you holding up?
- 有什麼事嗎      - 噢
- What's the matter?        - Ohh.
我就是問 你還好嗎
I said how are you holding up?
這是個白癡問題 你吃什麼了嗎
It's a stupid question. Get some food?
我吃了點奶酪
Oh, uh, i had some cheese.
你就吃了點奶酪嗎 混蛋
You had some cheese, asshole?
我給你弄點東西來
I'll get you something.
- 我什麼都不想吃      - 珍妮
- I don't want anything.        - Hey, Janine!
- 你確定嗎      - 怎麼了
- Sure?        - What?
- 我什麼都不想吃      - 沒什麼
- I don't want anything.        - Never mind.
- 怎麼了      - 沒事 忽略我
- What?        - Forget it. Skip it.
你說的我一句也聽不見
I can't hear a goddamn word you're saying.
什麼
What?
李吃東西了嗎
Did Lee get food?
他沒有 什麼
He didn't-- what?
李吃東西了嗎
Did Lee get food?
沒有 他不想吃
No! He doesn't want any.
- 沒事      - 我給他拿點東西
- We're good.        - I'll make him a plate.
別管了 他不要
Forget it. He doesn't--
沒事了
we're fine.
他什麼都不想吃
He doesn't want any--
我叫希爾薇來過夜可以嗎
hey, is it okay if i invite Sylvie over?
她是哪一個來著
Which one is she?
褐色頭髮那個
She's the one with the... The brown hair.
不行
No.
不行是什麼意思
What do you mean, no?
我不喜歡她
I don't like her.
我不想讓她現在出現在我家
I don't want her in the house right now.
為什麼 你連話都不用和她說
Why not? You don't even have to talk to her.
不好意思 你可以去她家 或者找你朋友
Sorry. Go to her house or call one of your friends.
就這樣
That's that.
如果我過去 你媽同意嗎
Would it be cool with your mom if I came over there?
我不知道
I have no idea.
好吧 明天聯繫
Okay. I'll talk to you tomorrow.
好吧 我也不能去她家
Well, I can't stay there, either.
那就對不起了
Sorry about that.
你要在這過夜嗎
You going to stay in here?
是啊 怎麼了
Yeah. Why not?
我想可能你會想睡在我爸的房間
I thought maybe you'd want to stay in dad's room.
怎麼 你希望我睡那嗎
Why, do you want me to?
沒 只是那個房間比較好
No. It's just a better room.
而且現在也空著
And he's not using it.
好吧 我睡你爸的房間
Okay. I'll stay in there.
反正我們也不會在這裏待多久了
We're not gonna be here that much longer anyway.
我不會搬去波士頓的 李叔叔
We're not moving to Boston, uncle Lee.
我現在不想談論這個問題
Well, I don't want to talk about that right now.
你說他留了錢 讓你好搬過來
You said he left you money so you could move.
是 那不見得...
Yeah. That doesn't mean--
況且 你在波士頓有什麼
anyway, what's in Boston?
你只是個清潔工
You're a janitor.
- 那怎麼了      - 你在哪兒不能當清潔工
- So what?        - You can do that anywhere.
這裏到處都是廁所
There's plenty of toilets
和堵塞的水槽
and clogged-up drains all over town.
- 我不想...      - 我所有的朋友都在這裏
- I don't want to--        - all my friends are here.
我加入了冰球隊
I'm on the hockey team.
我加入了籃球隊
I'm on the basketball team.
我現在還要保養我們的船
I got to maintain our boat now.
我每周有兩天要去喬治的船上幫忙
I work on George's boat two days a week.
我有兩個女朋友
I got two girlfriends,
我還加入了樂隊
and I'm in a band.
你只是昆西的一個清潔工
You're a janitor in Quincy.
你他媽有什麼好在乎自己住在哪裏的
What the hell do you care where you live?
我要去睡了
I got to go to sleep.
晚安
Good night.
你今晚住哪
Where are you going to stay tonight?
我不知道 汽車旅館吧
I don't know. A motel.
你什麼時候該給我打電話
What time you going to call me?
我到旅館的時候
When I get to the motel.
如果我到了九點還沒你消息
I want to hear from you by 9:00,
我就會報警
or I'm going to call the cops.
- 明白嗎      - 明白 明白
- Understand?        - Yes. Yes.
帕特裏克 來跟你李叔叔說再見
Patrick, come say goodbye to your uncle Lee!
- 沒關係      - 不 有關係
- It's okay.        - No, it's not.
帕特裏克
Patrick!
來了
Coming!
我會來看他的
I'm going to see him.
再見 李叔叔
Goodbye uncle Lee.
再會
So long.
小帕
Patty?
我有點不太對勁
I think there's something wrong with me.
什麼意思 你病了嗎
What do you mean? Like what? Are you sick?
我不知道
I don't know!
- 我感覺非常奇怪      - 你生病了嗎
- I feel really weird!        - Are you sick?
我突然覺得很恐慌
I think I'm havin' a panic attack.
什麼意思
What do you mean? Hey.
我不知道 我感覺...
I don't know, I mean...
你能把那該死的東西弄出去嗎
Could you get that shit outta here, please?
把什麼弄出來
Get rid of what?
我不知道 我不知道
I don't know, I don't know!
吃的嗎
The food?
你想讓我把那些吃的給扔了嗎
You want me to get rid of the food?
帕特裏克 喂
Patrick? Hey.
你要我帶你去醫院嗎
Do you want me to take you to the hospital?
不要 我不知道
No. I don't know.
你要我打給你朋友嗎
Do you want me to call your friends?
- 我不知道      - 你想讓我做什麼
- I don't know.        - What do you want me to do?
小帕 你要睡了嗎
Patty, are you going to bed?
別管我
Leave me alone.
我覺得我不能讓你關著門
I don't think I should let you keep the door shut.
走開
Just go away.
我會走的 你把門打開
I will. Just open up the door.
去你媽的
Fuck you.
天哪 你有毛病嗎
Jesus Christ, what's your problem?
我說了 把門打開 你是崩潰了嗎
I said open up the door. Are you havin' a breakdown?
我要帶你去醫院嗎
Shall we take you to the hospital?
不用 不用 不用
No! No! No!
我只是抓狂了
I'm just freakin' out.
好 沒事 但是我不能讓你關著門抓狂
Okay, fine, but I can't let you freak out with the door closed.
而且如果你每次看到冰凍的雞都要抓狂的話
And if you're gonna freak out every time you see a frozen chicken
我想我們應該去醫院看看
I think we should go to the hospital.
我對這種情況一無所知
I don't know anything about this.
我只是不想讓他待在冰櫃裏
I just don't like him bein' in the freezer!
你已經表達地很清楚了
You've expressed that very clearly.
我也不想
I don't like it either.
但是我們什麼辦法都沒有
There's nothin' we can do about it.
我不會煩你 我就坐在這
I'm not gonna bother you. I'm just gonna sit here
等你稍微好點了我就走
until you calm down.
好了 我現在好點了
All right, I'm calmer now.
所以你可以出去了嗎
Can you please just go away?
不行
No.
好酷
Cool!
他們給你發多少工資
How much are they payin' you?
最低工資加這個房間
Minimum wage plus the room.
好吧
All right.
咱們去買點傢俱回來
Let's go get some furniture.
我有傢俱了
I got furniture.
你才沒有
No, you don't.
這也算傢俱嗎
This doesn't count as furniture.
這連個房間都不算
This is not a room.
咱們一塊兒去買點傢俱吧
Let's go get some furniture
別煩我
get off my back.
小帕 過來 走吧
Patty, come on. Let's go.
走吧
Let's go.
放這兒
There we go.
好了
All right.
好多了吧?
Better?
好多了
Better.
聽著
So, listen.
在你放假之前 我們都可以待在這
We can stay here until your school lets out.
好嗎
Okay?
這樣我也有時間把波士頓那邊安排好
That'll give me time to set things up in Boston better.
暑假的時候你也可以跟著喬治幹點什麼
Maybe you can do some stuff with George in the summer if you want,
這樣你就不會一夜之間就告別了原來的生活
and you don't get jerked out of your life overnight.
行嗎
Okay?
你是在問我的意見還是在告訴我呢
Are you askin' me or tellin' me?
我是在告訴你我只能做到這樣了
I'm tellin' you that's the best I can do.
那問我行不行還有什麼必要呢
Then what the fuck do you care whether it's okay with me or not?
波士頓離這裏只有四十五分鐘車程而已
It's 45 minutes away.
想回來隨時都行
You can come back here any time you want.
- 從昆西?      - 沒錯
- From Quincy?        - Yeah.
起碼要一個半小時好嗎 你是在跟我開玩笑嗎
It's an hour and a-- is that a joke?
起碼一個半小時的車程
It's an hour and a half at least!
- 不是的      - 而且還會堵車
- No, it's not.        - You gotta include the other cars!
從這到羅克斯伯裏不可能只用半個小時
You couldn't get from here to Roxbury in half an hour
你他媽開個宇宙飛船都沒那麼快
if you flew in a fuckin' spaceship!
好吧 去你的
Okay, fuck it.
給我午飯錢
I need lunch money.
- 嘿 帕特裏克     - 嘿 帕特裏克
- Hey, Patrick!        - Hey, Patrick!
- 嘿 帕特裏克      - 帕特裏克 帕特裏克
- Hey, Patrick!        - Patrick! Patrick!
你要去看福音嗎
So, are you going to Godspell?
我正想著呢
I'm thinking about it.
好啊 拜
All right, 'Kay. Bye.
這倆也是你女朋友嗎
Those your girlfriends, too?
她們倒是想
They wish.
你給喬治幫忙 他不是會給你錢的嗎
Doesn't George give you money for working on his boat?
是啊 我存著呢
Yeah, but I'm savin' that.
- 存著幹嘛      - 買新發動機
- For what?        - New motor.
你是要去看福音嗎
You going to Godspell?
天吶
Aw, come on.
別吵了
Aw, come on!
你好
Hello.
嗨 是李嗎
Hello, Lee?
李?
Lee?
李 是李嗎
Lee, is that you?
能聽見嗎
Hello?
你的手怎麼了
What happened to your hand?
不小心劃傷的
I cut it.
說得好像我看不出來一樣
Oh. For a minute there i didn't know what happened.
你憑什麼不告訴我
Is there some reason why you didn't tell me
我媽打電話來了
my mom tried to call me?
她還說你把她電話給掛了
She wrote me you hung up on her.
她現在在埃塞克斯
She's in Essex.
想讓我過去吃個飯 見見她的未婚夫
She wants me to come have lunch and meet her fiancee.
你是怎麼想的
What'd you think?
是覺得她不能聯繫我嗎
She couldn't get in touch with me?
我掛她電話是因為我不知道怎麼跟她說
I hung up on her because i didn't know what to say to her.
我沒告訴你是因為我不知道怎麼跟你說
And I didn't tell you because 'cause I didn't know what to say to you.
對不起
I'm sorry.
你不能阻止我跟她來往
You can't stop me talkin' to her.
我才懶得管你
I don't give a shit what you do.
說得好聽 你都不讓我女朋友來過夜
No, but you won't let my girlfriend stay over,
你就這麼討厭我媽
You hate my mother so much
討厭到連她打電話來了都不告訴我
you won't even tell me she called.
你寧願把我拖到到昆西去 毀了我的人生
You'd rather drag me back to Quincy and ruin my life
也不願意讓別人當我的監護人
than let somebody else be my guardian--
沒有別人了
there is nobody else.
我可以跟我媽在埃塞克斯生活
I can live in Essex with my mom.
不 不行
No, you can't.
她已經不酗酒了 而且她想讓我過去
She's not an alcoholic anymore and she wants me
那所有的問題都迎刃而解了
to stay with her, then that solves all our problems.
我還是可以坐原來的巴士去現在的學校
I can take the same bus to my same school
我可以不用換新朋友
and keep all my friends,
還能留下我的船 你就可以回波士頓去了
and the boat, and you can go back to Boston,
願意的話可以抽空回來看看我什麼的都行
and still check in on me, or whatever, if you want to...
我不能這麼做
I can't do that.
為什麼
Why not?
小帕 我很抱歉掛了她的電話
Patty, I'm sorry I hung up on her.
我待會兒給她回一個過去
I'll call her back,
如果她跟我說話還有點人樣
and if she seems semi-human to me,
我會讓你去跟她和她未婚夫一起吃飯
you can go have lunch with her and her fiancee.
就這樣
That's it.
我不想再談這件事了
I don't wanna talk about this anymore.
好的 等前面沒船了
Okay, soon as we're clear,
就打開發動機看看
open it up and we'll see what we can do.
好
Okay.
李
Oh. Lee?
- 嘿      - 嘿 最近怎麼樣啊
- Hey.        - Hey, what do you say?
- 還好嗎      - 我還行 你呢
- How are you?        - Yeah, I'm good. How are you?
- 還行      - 嗯
- All right.        - Yeah.
喬的事我很抱歉
I'm really, uh-- I'm really sorry to hear about Joe.
沒事 多謝
I know, yeah, thanks.
帕特裏克怎麼樣
How's Patrick doing?
- 還好      - 是嗎
- Good.        - Yeah?
- 是啊      - 那就好
- Yeah.        - Good.
最近在忙什麼呢
What's going on? What are ya--
我最近回來了 打算待到暑假
you know, I'm back, I'm thinking about staying until the summer.
你這邊還缺不缺人手
I was wondering if you had any work.
我想找點活幹幹
I'm looking to pick up some hours.
當然可以了
Sure, sure, um...
沃爾特現在剛好到波士頓去了
Walt is down in Boston, so...
- 是嗎      - 如果你想過來的話
- Oh, he is?        - Yeah, he should be back tomorrow
- 他明天下午應該回來了      - 他明天回來是嗎
- if you want to come by.        - He's coming back up tomorrow?
給他打個電話吧
Yeah, yeah. Give him a call.
好 我會的
Okay. I will give him a call.
- 好主意      - 我會的
- That's a good idea.        - I'll do that.
- 好      - 那行
- Absolutely.        - Okay. All right.
- 好      - 見到你很高興
- All right.        - Good to see you.
- 謝了 傑瑞      - 沒事
- Thanks, Jerry.        - All right.
我不想在這再見到他
I don't want to see him in here again.
再見 帕特裏克
Bye, Patrick.
星期天想去看球賽嗎
Want to watch the football game on Sunday?
- 好啊      - 再會 帕特裏克
- Sure.        - So long, Patrick.
- 再見 帕特裏克      - 再見
- Bye, Patrick.        - See you guys.
發動機怎麼樣了
How's the motor?
喬治說現在活塞隨時都可能打穿氣缸
George says the piston's gonna go right through the block any minute now.
很不幸 這就真是個問題了
Unfortunately that's a problem.
如果我們沒法讓船跑起來的話 我們就養不起它了
We can't afford to keep a boat if we can't run it,
而且要是發動機壞了 船就別想跑起來了
and we can't run it if it's got a broken motor.
我們去借錢吧
Let's take out a loan.
然後用什麼還
And pay it back with what?
當然是把船租出去然後用租金還啊
We hire it out 'til we pay the loan back, obviously.
告訴你一個不幸的消息
Unfortunately for you,
二十一歲之前 你的財產都由我來管
I'm in charge of your finances until you turn 21,
而我不太願意替你去
and I'm not comfortable takin' out enormous loans
借那麼一大筆錢
on your behalf.
樂隊還有訓練
I have band practice.
能不能先送我回去拿點東西
Can you drive me home to get my stuff
然後再把我送到桑迪家
then drive me over to Sandy's house?
可以啊
Sure.
你為什麼不去學個駕照呢 我又不是你的司機
Why don't you take a drivers' s course? I'm not your chauffeur.
因為我答應爸爸十七歲之前不開車
'Cause dad made me promise not to drive 'til I was 17.
行吧 那就這麼著吧
Okay, we'll stick with that then.
你想留下來吃晚餐嗎
Do you wanna stay for dinner?
我覺得桑迪的媽媽挺喜歡你的
I think Sandy's mother likes you.
她才不喜歡我
No, she doesn't.
我正好知道她喜歡你呢
I happen to know that she does.
這對我們倆都是好事
This could be good for both of us.
還是算了吧
I'd really rather not.
你好歹留下來跟她聊聊天
Well, can you at least just like hang out with her
半小時就行 那樣她就不會每隔二十秒就來敲一次門了
for half an hour so I can be alone with Sandy
我和桑迪也能獨處一會兒
without her mother knockin' on the door every twenty seconds?
哥們 行不行啊
Come on, man.
你跟她聊聊天有什麼難的
All you gotta do is talk to her.
你就不能幫我這個小忙嗎
Why can't you help me out a little bit for once
不要只會拖我去見律師
instead of draggin' me to the lawyers
或者去殯儀館 太平間
and the funeral parlor and the morgue?
不管怎麼說 她人很好啊
Anyway, she's really nice.
停停停
Stop, stop, stop, stop. Stop, stop.
- 奧托      - 怎麼了 我又慢了?
- Otto...        - What, I'm too slow?
太快了 哥們兒 你一直拖著我們走
Too fast man. You're dragging.
你快太多了
You're way too fast, man.
我又快了啊
I'm too fast.
兄弟 你他媽都快到天上去了
Dude, you're like pulling out of the fucking station ahead of me.
你們這些人少說兩句不行嗎
Oh my god, you guys, leave him alone.
你到底有沒有認真對待樂隊的事情
Dude, like, are you serious about this band, or what?
行了 行了
Okay, all right, all right.
- 把他開除吧      - 別來煩我
- Just lay off him.        - Get off my back.
好吧 我們都冷靜冷靜
All right, everybody just chill here.
再來一遍吧
Let's just, um... Let's just go again.
我們是 響徹雲霄
We are stentorian.
帕特裏克是我最喜歡的人之一了
Patrick is one of my favorite people.
那挺好的
That's good.
你們在樓上怎麼樣呀
How's it goin' up there, you guys?
挺好的 謝啦
It's going... It's going fine, thanks!
但我們現在正忙著呢
But we're right in the middle of something.
我們正在專心研究這些復合分數呢
We're just banging out those compound fractions.
好歹我們還知道他們在哪 對吧
At least we know where they are, right?
這倒是真的
That's true.
你要拆幾個
How many of those you generally gotta go through
才能挑出一個能用的
before you pick a winner?
我就是想看看要是老有人打擾你
I'd like to see you use one of these goddamn things
你還行不行
with all these interruptions.
操
Oh, fuck me!
怎麼了 你沒事吧
What happened? Are you ok?
我被你的傻逼娃娃屋給絆倒了
I tripped over your fuckin' doll house.
天吶 你把它弄壞了嗎
Oh my god, did you break it?
我不知道 順便告訴你我沒事
I don't know. I'm fine though, by the way.
天吶
Oh my god.
我五歲的時候外婆就把這個娃娃屋給我了
My grandmother gave me that when I was five years old.
這就是她小的時候
It was literally her doll house
她的那個娃娃屋
from when she was a little girl.
那你幹嘛把它放在地上啊
Then what's it doin' on the fuckin' floor?
娃娃屋就是放在地上的啊 不然怎麼玩
Um, it's a doll house, that's where you play with it!
孩子們 你們怎麼了
Kids, what is going on up there?
沒事 帕特裏克被外婆的娃娃屋給絆倒了
Nothing! Patrick just stubbed his toe on mummer's doll house,
不過沒事了
but it's okay!
桑迪 那可是我媽媽的娃娃屋
Sandy, that doll house belonged to my mother.
- 我知道 媽媽      - 如果你要把它砸碎的話
- Yes I know, mom.        - If you're gonna smash it to pieces...
這玩意兒還好好的呢 一點沒壞
Nobody is smashin' it to pieces! It's fine!
別擔心 吉爾 反正我沒事 我的腳趾頭也沒事
Don't worry, Jill, I'm okay. My toe's gonna be okay.
你到底還想不想操我了
Do you want to fuck me or not?
想啊
Yes.
李 你還想再喝點啤酒嗎
Could I get you another beer, Lee?
不用了 謝謝
I'm good. Thank you.
我先失陪一下 就一會兒
Would you excuse me, Lee, one sec?
當然
Sure.
- 戴上了嗎      - 是的 簡直奇跡
- Is it on?        - Yes. It's a miracle.
來吧 抓緊時間
Okay, hurry up.
稍等一下下
Ow... One second please!
給我起開
Get outta my way!
不好意思
I'm sorry.
怎麼了
What's up?
我真是太抱歉了 我知道你們在用功
I'm really sorry, i know you're trying to work,
但我在樓下真是一秒鐘都坐不下去了
but I can't sit down there much longer.
怎麼了 出什麼事嗎
Why? What's the problem?
他就是不說話
He won't talk.
我已經沒話找話半小時了
I've been trying to make conversation for half an hour.
- 真的嗎      - 怎麼了
- Are you serious?        - What's the matter?
我知道我不是世界上
I realize I'm not the most fascinating
- 最有魅力的人      - 媽 你說什麼呢
- person in the world--        - oh, mom!
但這樣子也太過分了
But it's very, very strained.
- 發生了什麼      - 你叔叔就是不肯開口說話
- What's going on?        - She can't get your uncle to talk.
他喜歡體育
He likes sports.
打擾到你們我真的很抱歉
I'm sorry to bust things up,
但是我還是想問問你們大概還要多久
but how much longer do you think you're gonna be?
要不你開一下電視看看有沒有體育節目
Could you maybe turn on a game?
- 真對不起      - 閉嘴吧你
- I'm sorry.        - Shut up.
媽媽 你別這樣
Mummy, please.
你真是幫了我的大忙
You were a tremendous help.
又不是我自己想坐在那的
I didn't ask to sit down there.
你就不能像其他大人一樣隨便閒聊兩句嗎
You can't make small talk like every other grown-up in the world?
- 不行      - 你就不能隨便扯點什麼瞎話打發掉半小時嗎
- No.        - You can't talk about boring bullshit for half an hour?
- 不行      - 嘿 現在銀行的利率怎麼樣
- No.        - Hey, how about those interest rates?
- 不行      - 嘿 我上次把我的3A卡給弄丟了
- No, I can't.        - Hey, I lost my triple a card.
- 不行      - 就像所有正常人一樣?
- Nope.        - Like everybody else?
不行 不好意思
Nope, sorry.
你真是個混蛋
You're a fucking asshole.
你說她住在哪來著
Where'd you say she lives?
因為這塊連房子的影子都沒有
'Cause there's, like, no houses here. None.
她是睡在睡袋裏嗎
What, does she live in a fucking sleeping bag?
鴿子山街119號
119 Pigeon hill street.
鴿子山街 還是鴿子山路?
Pigeon hill street, or Pigeon hill road?
- 鴿子山街      - 好 所以是街
- Pigeon hill street        - Okay, Pigeon hill street.
- 還是鴿子山區      - 街
- Pigeon hill court.        - Street.
- 鴿子山路      - 街
- Pigeon hill road.        - Street.
- 街 知道了      - 我們要去鴿子山街
- Fine, Pigeon hill--        - Pigeon hill street.
- 這是鴿子山路      - 好
- This is pigeon hill road.        - Okay.
- 你是沒有導航嗎      - 沒有 你沒看見我正盯著手機上的動畫看嗎
- You have no GPS whatsoever?        - No, I have a little fucking cartoon.
- 所以你是需要我幫你嗎      - 不用了
- You want me to punch it in for you?        - No, I don't.
我搞定了 謝了
I've got it, thank you.
聽著
Okay, listen.
你現在是不是很緊張
Are you nervous?
緊張啊
Yeah, I'm nervous.
你真是太聰明了 這都知道
What are you, a fuckin' genius?
算了
Okay, skip it.
我只是想說如果氣氛很尷尬就給我發短信
Just want you to text me if anything gets weird.
好 謝謝
Okay. Thank you.
老天啊 這真的是我的帕特裏克嗎
Oh my gosh. Is that my Patrick?
你好 媽媽
Hi, mom.
我太高興了
I'm so happy.
進來吧 歡迎來我家
Come in. Welcome to my home.
帕特裏克 這是我家那位
Patrick. This is my fella.
傑弗裏 這是帕特裏克
Jeffrey, this is Patrick...
終於見到你了 帕特裏克
Great to finally meet you, Patrick.
- 見到你很高興      - 是啊
- Nice to meet you.        - Yeah.
這是李
And this is Lee.
你好 歡迎
Hey, welcome.
- 謝謝      - 我叫傑弗裏
- Thanks.        - Jeffrey.
我是李
Lee.
李 你確定你真的沒法留下來吃午餐嗎
Now, Lee, are you sure you can't stay for lunch?
我確定
I'm positive. Yeah.
好吧
All right.
來吧
Come, come.
你們真的不用我幫忙嗎
Oh, are you sure-- i can't help you--
不用 謝謝 親愛的
no thanks, honey.
你好好休息就是了
Your job is to relax.
休息就是你的頭號任務 聽見了嗎
That is your number one assignment, okay?
好 那我就不客氣了
Okay, all right. I'm really gonna apply myself.
不 我只是開個玩笑而已
No, I was just joking.
我知道 我也開玩笑呢
I know you were. So was I.
你們倆相處的怎麼樣
How we gettin' along?
- 非常好      - 很好
- Great.        - Great.
你不用這麼禮貌的 知道嗎
You don't have to be so polite, you know.
我沒有很禮貌啊
I'm not being polite.
吃飯前你要不要先洗個手
Did you wanna wash your hands before we eat?
好
Yes.
讓我們感激上帝所賜予的食物
For what we are about to receive, let us give thanks.
- 阿門      - 阿門
- Amen.        - Amen.
阿門
Amen.
你可以說阿門 帕特裏克
You can say "amen", Patrick.
不會有人強迫你信教
Nobody's tryin' to recruit you.
我說了
I did say "amen".
是嗎 好吧
Oh, you did? Okay.
其實你也可以不說
Well, you don't have to.
我知道 我只是很小聲地說了一下
Yeah, I know. I just said it really quietly.
沒關係的 寶貝
Oh. It's fine, honey.
我知道 看到我你一定覺得很震驚
Look, I know I'm gonna be a shock to you.
畢竟不只是變了一丁點
In a lot of ways.
但我希望那是好的震驚
I'm hoping it's a good shock.
當然了
Yeah.
你還要點什麼嗎 帕特裏克
You need anything else, Patrick?
但願這些菜還合你胃口
I hope everything's okay.
當然了 都很好吃
Oh yeah, everything's great.
你不用這麼拘束
You don't have to be so formal.
我沒有啊
I'm not.
我覺得你媽媽只是想
I think your mother wants you to feel--
我只是想讓你知道這也是你的家
I'm just sayin' that this is your home, too.
我希望這裏也能成為你的家
I want it to be.
我知道
And I know...
I know, uh...
事情對你來說都變了
Things are different for you.
但是 我也不知道怎麼說了
Anyway, I don't know.
沒關係的
That's okay.
你在學校都學些什麼呢 帕特裏克
What are you studying at school, Patrick?
就那些東西啊
Oh, well, the usual stuff.
這樣吧 我去去就來
You know what? I'm gonna be right back.
你們誰需要我從廚房帶什麼嗎
Does anybody need anything from the kitchen?
- 不用了 謝謝      - 什麼都不需要
- No, thanks. Thank you.        - I'm good, no.
你嘗了這個青豆沒
Did you get some string beans?
還沒呢 謝謝
Oh, no, not yet. Thank you.
我...
Let me, um...
我去看下她在裏面做什麼
Let me just see what she's doin' in there.
她看起來怎麼樣
So what was she like?
我不知道 她挺緊張的
I don't know. She was pretty nervous.
是嗎
Yeah?
那個男的什麼樣
What was that guy like?
十足的基督徒
He was very Christian.
你知道我們也是基督徒吧
You know, we're Christian, too, right?
我知道
Yes, I know that.
你知道所有的天主教徒都是基督教吧
You are aware that Catholics are Christians?
是的 我知道
Yes, I am aware of that.
不管怎麼樣 聽你這麼說她應該是好多了
Well, it sounds like she's doin' better, anyway.
不酗酒了
She's not drinkin'.
也不在精神病院了
She's not in the psych ward.
哇哦
Wow.
你哇什麼
Wow, what?
你真是不顧一切想要甩掉我
You'll do anything to get rid of me.
- 你說什麼      - 你聽到我說什麼了
- What?        - You heard me.
胡說八道
That's not true.
親愛的帕特裏克 我寫信來是為了感謝你今天能來
Dear Patrick, I'm writing to thank you for today.
你的到來對於你母親來說意義重大
Your visit meant the world to your mom.
你願意重新回到她的生活
We are both deeply grateful for the love and trust
所表現出的愛與信任讓我們十分感激
you've shown by offering to rejoin her life,
但我覺得你似乎不應該匆忙地將她
but I feel it would be unfair to your mom to rush her along
趕上這條漫長而艱難的道路
the long and challenging road ahead,
所以我希望你可以給我回信
and so I'm going to ask you to write to me
以安排日後的見面
in future to arrange any further visits.
我希望這封信不會打擾…
I hope you won't take this as an intrusion--
你的朋友們今晚在哪呢
where are your friends tonight?
我不知道
I don't know.
為什麼不打給那個叫桑迪的姑娘呢
Why don't you call that girl Sandy,
- 看她會不會過來      - 不用了謝謝
- see if she'll come over?        - No, thanks.
不過做得不錯
Nice try, though.
你想要對誰開槍 你還是我
Who are you going to shoot, you or me?
你知道這些槍值多少錢嗎
Do you know what these things are worth?
不知道
No.
我想把它們賣了
Want to try and sell them
這樣就可以給船換個新馬達了
so you can have a motor for the boat?
還真是個好主意
That's a really good idea.
太棒了
This is awesome.
是很不錯
你想開嗎
Do you want to drive?
好啊
Sure.
來吧
All right.
天啊
Oh! Oh, my god!
- 抱歉      - 沒事 沒事
- I'm so sorry.        - That's all right.
沒事 穩一下方向
That's all right. Just straighten her out.
- 天啊      - 穩一下方向
- Oh, my god.        - Straighten her out.
- 沒事      - 真是抱歉
- That's okay.        - Sorry.
我去買點東西
Hey, I got to run some chores.
過幾個小時回來
I'll be back in a couple hours.
- 你們要帶點什麼嗎      - 不用 謝謝
- You want anything?        - No, thank you.
不用了 謝謝 錢德勒先生
No, thanks, Mr. Chandler.
謝謝
Thank you.
都是陷阱
Set-up city.
你在說什麼
What are you talking about?
希爾薇·米根還好嗎
Oh, yeah? How's Sylvie Mcgann?
誰
Who?
開門吧
Just open the door.
我不覺得這是我們的責任 但是...
I didn't think it was our responsibility, but--
是啊 我的意思是 他們應該...
Yeah, I guess. I mean, they could have--
沒事
it's okay.
李
Lee.
嗨
Hi.
蕾切爾 這是李
Rachel, this is Lee.
- 你好      - 李 蕾切爾
- Hello.        - Lee, this is Rachel.
你好 你好
Hi. Hi.
這是迪倫
And this is Dylan.
你不太看得到他
Uh, you can't see him too good.
你好 迪倫
Hi, Dylan.
是個帥小伙
Very handsome.
蘭迪 我去開車 然後過來接你吧
Randi, you want me to get the car and pick you up?
- 好      - 不用 我得走了
- Yeah.        - That's okay. I got to go.
那個...我們能...
Actually, could-- could we, uh,
我們能聊兩句嗎
could we talk for a second?
- 當然      - 好
- Sure.        - Okay.
我去把車開過來 幾分鐘就好
I'll just pull around. Just be a few minutes.
- 好 謝謝      - 很高興認識你
- Okay. Thanks.        - Nice to meet you.
- 我也是      - 我馬上就回來
- Yeah. You, too.        - Be right back.
我也沒什麼重要的事要說
I don't have anything big to say.
沒事
That's okay.
只是...
I just--
我知道你來這裏了 我想...
I know you've been around, and i--
我只是來把帕特裏克安頓好
I've just been getting Patrick settled in.
他看起來似乎還不錯
It seems like he's doing pretty good, huh?
畢竟出了這種事
Considering.
我想他應該還不錯
I think he is, yeah.
我猜你還不知道
I guess you don't know this,
不過我...
but I, uh...
其實我和喬一直有聯繫
I really kept in touch with Joe.
- 不 我知道的      - 見不到帕特裏克
- No, I knew that.        - It's been kind of weird
我還有點不習慣 噢 好吧
for me not seeing Patrick. Oh. Oh, okay.
我不知道
I-- I didn't know.
你可以見他 如果你想見的話
Uh, you could see him if you want.
我們可以一起吃個午飯嗎
Could we ever have lunch?
你是說我們 你和我嗎
You mean us, you and me?
是的
Yeah.
因為我
Because I, uh...
我對你說了很多很過分的話
I said a lot of terrible things to you.
沒事
No.
但是我
But i--
我知道你再也不
I know you never--
可能不想再和我說話了
maybe you don't want to talk to me.
- 不是那樣的      - 讓我說完
- It's not that.        - Let me finish.
但是
However--
我的心碎了
my heart was broken.
永遠都不會好了
It's always going to be broken.
我知道你的心也碎了
And I know yours is broken, too.
但我不用帶著...
But I don't have to carry--
我說的那些話
I said things that--
我對你說的那些話簡直太該死了
I should fucking burn in hell for what I said to you.
別這樣
No. No.
- 真的是太...      - 不 不 不 不
- It was--        - no, no, no, no.
不 蘭迪
Randi, no.
對不起
I'm just sorry.
這 我 我不能
It-- i-- I can't ex-- i can't--
我愛你
I love you.
我可能不該這麼對你說
Maybe I shouldn't say that.
沒事的
No, you can say that.
只是
It's just--
抱歉 我得走了
I'm sorry. I've got to go.
我們不能一起吃午飯嗎
We couldn't have lunch?
真的很抱歉 還是不了吧
I'm really sorry. I don't think so.
謝謝你告訴我這些
I thank you for saying everything you said.
你不能就這樣死去
You can't just die.
我沒有 我不會
I'm not. I'm not. I'm not.
親愛的
But, honey-- honey--
我希望你能快樂
and i-- i want you to be happy.
親愛的 我看到你在附近
Honey, I see you walking around here,
我只是想告訴你
and I just want to tell you--
我想和你說話 蘭迪
I would want to talk to you, randi,
- 但是 李      - 拜託 我 我
- but, Lee--        - Please, i-- i-- i--
因為 我
because-- i--
- 李...      - 我
- Lee--        - um, I'm--
- 我試圖      - 李 你要
- I'm trying to--        - Lee, you've got to--
我不知道
I don't know what--
這並不是
look, this is not--
我不想折磨你
I don't want to torture you.
你沒有折磨我
You're not torturing me.
我只是想告訴你
I just want to tell you
我錯了
that I was wrong.
不 不
No. No.
你不明白 我什麼都...
You don't understand. There's nothing--
我什麼都不在乎了
there's nothing there.
- 什麼都不在乎了      - 不是這樣的
- There's nothing there.        - That's not true.
- 那不是真的       - 讓我說
- That's not true.        - Let me say this.
你不明白
You don't understand.
我明白
I understand you.
我不知道該
I don't know what to--
我知道你明白
I know you understand me.
我...我得走了
I-- i-- I've got to go.
- 不要      - 對不起
- Don't.        - I'm sorry.
對不起
I'm sorry.
- 抱歉      - 沒事
- Pardon me.        - It's all right.
操
Shit.
你看到了嗎
Did you see that?
你想打我們 你想打我們?
You want to hit us? Want to hit us?
- 操你媽的      - 來啊 你們這幫混蛋
- God damn it!        - Come on, you little bastard!
小心 小心 小心
Look out, look out, look out.
Look out, look out, look out!
別打了 別打了
Break it up! Break it up!
- 喬治      - 別打了
- George!        - Break it up!
放開他 別打了
Get off him! Break it up!
退後 喬治
Back off, George!
- 操他媽的      - 喬治 你出去
- Fuck him!        - George, get out of here!
- 別打了      - 喬治
- Break him up!        - George!
喬治 把他趕出去
Get him out of here, George!
這是喬∙錢德勒的弟弟
He's Joey Chandler's brother.
- 退後 退後      - 該死的
- Back off, back off.        - Fucking dude--
- 操      - 喂 冷靜點
- oh, fuck--        - hey, settle down.
操他媽的 操他媽的
Fuck him! Fuck him!
- 他就是個該死的蠢貨      - 冷靜點
- He's a fucking douche bag!        - Settle down.
冷靜點 你贏了 好嗎
Settle down. You won, all right?
去你媽的
Fuck that motherfucker.
- 冷靜點      - 好了 哥們
- Settle down.        - Okay, brother.
- 行了嗎      - 你贏了 好嗎
- You good?        - You won, all right?
- 行了嗎      - 操他媽的
- Are we cool?        - Fuck him.
操他媽的
Fuck him!
過來 放開
Come here. Get off.
- 放開 放開      - 放開他
- Get off. Get off.        - Leave him--
- 操你媽的      - 快他媽放開 放開他
- fuck you!        - Get the fuck off. Get him--
要送他去醫院嗎
Should he go to the hospital?
不用 只是皮外傷
I don't think so. Nothing's broken.
他們用什麼打的他
What did they fucking hit him with,
棒球棍嗎
a baseball bat?
他們都說是他先動的手
They all just said he started swinging.
帕特裏克在哪裏
Where's Patrick?
他和孩子們在一起
He's with the kids.
我讓他們去買漢堡了
I sent them out for burgers.
不 不 不 不
No, no, no, no.
- 李 坐下      - 坐好
- Lee, sit down.        - Sit down.
坐好 沒事的
Sit down. It's all right.
我把錢給你
Let me give you some money.
李 別這樣 我都付了
Lee, please, I got it.
- 我把錢給你      - 就這樣
- I'll give you some money.        - Put that away.
- 拜託 別這樣 我付了      - 把錢收起來
- Please, no. I got it.        - Put your money away.
我付了 算我的
I got it. It's on me.
我煮了點咖啡 喝點吧
I made you some coffee. Come on. Drink this.
- 別這樣      - 別這樣
- Come on.        - Come on.
別這樣 夥計
Come on, buddy.
喝一點吧
Just have a little.
沒事 我去給你拿點冰塊敷臉 好嗎
It's all right. I'm going to get you some ice for your face, okay?
沒事
It's all right.
有什麼要我幫忙的嗎 李叔叔
Can I get you anything, uncle Lee?
不用 謝謝 夥計
Oh, no, thanks, buddy.
好吧 那我去睡覺了
All right. I'm going to go to bed.
- 晚安       - 晚安
- Good night.        - Good night.
爸爸
Daddy.
怎麼了 親愛的
Yes, honey?
難道你沒發現 我們燒起來了嗎
Can't you see we're burning?
不 親愛的 沒有
No, honey. You're not burning.
著火了 著火了
Fire. Fire.
李叔叔 這是什麼怪味
Uncle Lee, what-- what is that smell?
我把醬汁燒糊了 沒事
I just burned the sauce. Everything's okay.
我在波士頓找了份工作 七月開始上班
I got a job in Boston. Starts in July.
做什麼
What is it?
保管員 修理工
Custodian, handyman.
但這次只用跑兩棟樓
But it's just two buildings this time, so...
那你在波士頓給我們
And what, uh, delightful Boston neighborhood
挑了什麼好小區了嗎
have you selected for us to live in?
- 沒有      - 什麼意思
- None.        - What do you mean?
你不用去波士頓
You don't have to move to Boston.
我會去查爾斯鎮
I want to be in Charlestown,
喬治會照顧你的
and George is going to take you.
什麼
What?
我上周和他談了談
I talked to him last week
解釋了現在的情況
and explained the situation to him.
小喬治今年秋天就要去波士頓大學上學了
Georgie junior's going to BU in the fall,
吉米明年就畢業
and Jimmy graduates next year.
在你十八歲之前 我們可以把這房子租出去
We can rent this house out until you turn 18.
十八歲之後你想住的話可以住回來
Then you come back and stay if you want.
等你二十一歲了 你就可以賣了它
When you turn 21, you're allowed to sell it
或者留著 隨你的便
or keep it or whatever you want to do.
等夏天過去了 肯定要把船租出去
We definitely have to hire out the boat when summer's over.
就像我們之前說過的那樣
Just like we talked about.
等你拿到執照
When you get your license,
我們到時候再決定怎麼辦
then we can-- we can just figure that out when it happens.
我還是托管人
I'm still the trustee.
但喬托付給我的財產方面的東西
But all the financial stuff that Joe set up for me
都會轉到喬治那裏
is going to get transferred over to George.
所以除了你不用搬家之外
So basically everything's staying the same,
一切照舊
except you don't have to move.
謝謝 但是 誰...
Thank you, but, like, who's--
他們就成了我的監護人了嗎
are they going to be my guardians, or are you going--
他們會收養你
they're going to adopt you.
總之 我目前是這麼打算的
Anyway, that's just how I set it up.
不過也不是一定要這樣 你說了算
You don't have to. It's up to you.
所以你就要這樣消失了嗎
So you're just going to disappear?
不
No.
我幫你打點好了一切 這樣你就可以留在這裏
I set it up this way so you could stay here.
他們也很高興能收養你
And they're really glad to have you.
- 他們...      - 我知道 我知道
- They--        - I know, I know.
他們很好
I mean, they're great, but...
但為什麼你不能留下
Why can't you stay?
別這樣 小帕
Come on, Patty.
我走不出來
I can't beat it.
對不起
I'm sorry.
你覺得怎麼樣
What do you think?
會沒事的
It's going to be okay.
你是斯坦·錢德勒的兒子嗎
Are you one of Stan Chandler's boys?
是的 我叫李
Yeah. I'm Lee.
很久以前 我常和你父親下西洋棋
I used to play chess with your father a long time ago.
他很厲害
He was a excellent chess player.
是的
That's him.
他去世了 是嗎
He's not still living, is he?
是的
No.
我聽聞
One of the sons
最近他的一個兒子也去世了
passed away recently, I heard.
是的 就是我哥 喬
Uh, yeah, my brother Joe.
他是個很不錯的人
Very personable man.
是的
Yeah.
我父親是在1959年去世的
My father passed away in 1959.
當時還很年輕
A young man.
在一搜捕撈金槍魚的船上工作
He worked on a tuna boat.
有一天早上他出海了
He got up one morning.
尋常天氣 一點都不惡劣
Same weather, nothing dramatic.
但他再也沒回來
And he never returned.
沒有信號 沒有呼救
No signals, no maydays.
也沒人知道到底發生了什麼
No one ever found out what happened to him.
我去買點冰激凌
I'm going to get some ice cream.
去吧
Go ahead.
能給我點錢嗎
Can I have some money?
嗯
Yes.
我什麼時候搬去和喬治住
So when am I supposed to move in with Georgie?
七月
July.
我現在都還沒有找到房子
I don't even have a place to live yet.
他們沒有給你安排公寓嗎
They don't give you an apartment?
有 但我想要有兩個房間的公寓
Yeah, but I'm looking for one with an extra room.
能放下一張沙發
A room for a pull-out sofa or--
為什麼
what for?
萬一你什麼時候想來看我呢
So you can come visit some time.
或者你想來波士頓參觀參觀大學
Or if you want to look at colleges in Boston,
到時候你就能住我那裏
you could stay overnight.
我不會去讀大學的
I'm not going to college.
行吧 那我用那個房間來堆我的雜物
All right, then I'll have an extra room for all my shit.
我們非得現在談這個嗎
Do we have to talk about this now?
不
No.
扔得好
Great throw.
別管它了
Just let it go.
注意了
Heads up.
奇遇電影字幕組
QY-174
翻譯：@阿囤小兄弟 @一隻醉丁 @不見老阿
@movie404 @魚飼料1 @Tien_Sun
時間軸：@Edandelion_ @一隻醉丁 @33-eR
@-GOOEY @沒什麼能難倒LeoQ
校對：@一個Delpy  @Florrie_likkke
特效：@一隻醉丁
更多資訊請關注官方公眾號：cinematik